♪ 好吧，现在你走了，这世界是我们的了
♪ Now that you're gone, the world is ours
派 拉 蒙
维亚康姆旗下公司
美国派拉蒙电影公司 出 品
\h协助出品 美国孩之宝
我们曾经是一群爱好和平的智能化机械种族
We were once a peaceful race of intelligent, mechanical beings.
但后来爆发了战争
But then came the war
一方是汽车人 为自由而战
between the Autobots, who fought for freedom
另一方则是霸天虎 却妄图称霸
and the Decepticons, who dreamt of tyranny.
敌强我弱 敌众我寡
Overmatched and outnumbered,
我们必败无疑
our defeat was all but certain.
但就在战争临近尾声之时
But in the war's final days,
一艘汽车人飞船冲出了纷飞的战火
one Autobot ship escaped the battle.
飞船上载着一批秘密货物
It was carrying a secret cargo,
它本可以改变我们母星的命运
which would have changed our planet's fate.
那是最后的拼死一搏
A desperate mission.
承载着我们最后的希望
Our final hope.
而这希望也破灭了
A hope that vanished.
VLA电波天文台新墨西哥州 1961年
一个在那里 一个在这里
One up there. One over there.
还有一个在这里
And one more down there.
有什么收获？
What you got?
探测到撞击
Impact detected.
确认发生撞击 接触时间为20:50
We have impact confirmed. Contact at 2250 GMT.
国家宇航局局长 兰利 弗吉尼亚州
什么？
What?
马上给我接通国防部长
Get me SecDef on the phone right away.
紧急 观测到深空轨迹 监测到月面撞击
国家安全指挥部 五角大楼
麦克·纳马拉部长 总统先生在等您
Mr. McNamara, the President is expecting you.
让鲍比进来
Get Bobby in here.
总统先生 最高机密
Mr. President, designation, top secret.
有一艘不明飞行物在在月球上坠落
We believe a UFO has crashed into the Moon.
苏联人应该也在调查此事
We think the Russians are onto it as well.
命令航天局要动用一切力量
Well, then you tell NASA to move heaven and earth.
我们得登上月球
We need to get to the moon.
我们得实现一次载人探月行动
We're going to attempt a manned mission.
航天局认为这得花上5年
NASA said it would take five years.
必须抢在苏联人之前登月
You get there before the Russians.
我相信我国人民能够齐聚一心全力以赴
I believe that this nation should commit itself
达成这个目标
to achieving the goal
在这个十年结束前
before this decade is out
人类将登陆到月球并且安全返回地球
of landing a man on the moon and returning him safely to the Earth.
启动发射程序
Ignition sequence start.
（8年后 1969年7月16日） 五 四 三 二 一
Five, four, three, two, one.
8年后 1969年7月16日
全部引擎工作正常
All engines running.
发射 已经发射
Liftoff. We have a liftoff.
时间是9点32分 阿波罗11号发射升空
Thirty-two minutes past the hour. Liftoff on Apollo 11.
尼尔·阿姆斯特朗报告阿波罗11号飞行轨道正确
Neil Armstrong reporting Apollo 11 on proper heading.
阿波罗11号开始了旅程
Apollo 11 is on the way,
乘着强焰之柱
riding that pillar of flame
由土星5号火箭喷射而出 奔向了25万英哩之外
from the Saturn V out there, 250,000 miles away,
月球正在那里静候着
where the moon is waiting
人类的首次造访
for man 's first arrival.
这里是休斯顿 现在准备降落 完毕
Houston, you're a go for landing. Over.
40英尺 下降2.5英尺 扬起了一些灰尘
Forty feet, down two and a half. Picking up some dust.
30英尺 下降2.5英尺 模糊的影子
Thirty feet, two and a half down. Faint shadow.
宇航通讯员 飞行
Capcom, flight.
向前4英尺 向右漂移一点点
Four forward. Drifting to the right a little.
下降0.5英尺
Down a half.
轻轻降落
Contact light.
好了 关闭引擎
Okay, engine stop.
休斯顿
Houston,
这里是静海基地
Tranquility Base here.
小鹰号登月舱已经着陆
The Eagle has landed.
收到着陆讯号 小鹰号
We copy you down, Eagle.
你们把大家的脸都快憋青了
You got a bunch of guys about to turn blue.
总算能松口气了
We're breathing again.
最高机密
大约有4亿人正在观看今日的直播
Perhaps 400 million persons are watching this broadcast today
见证这一时代最伟大的成就…
of the greatest event in our time
这也是铭载史册的一大壮举
and one of the great events of all recorded history.
我下到了梯子的底部
I'm at the foot of the ladder.
好的 现在走下了登月舱
Okay, I'm gonna step off the LEM now.
这是我个人的一小步…
That's one small step for man,
但却是人类的一大步
one giant leap for mankind.
- 准备好了没？ - 好了 长官
- Are we good? - Yes, sir.
转到1092非正式频道…
Unofficial time on the first step, 109....
阿波罗11号 这里是休斯顿 完毕
Apollo 11? This is Houston, over.
小鹰号 我们遇到了讯号干扰
Eagle, we're getting a signal interference.
你们听到了吗？
Do you copy?
刚刚得到证实
We now have had confirmation
暂时出现中断
of loss of signal
与阿波罗11号的联系
from the Apollo 11.
阿波罗11号此刻正在月球的背面
The Apollo 11 is, at the moment, on the far side of the moon.
尼尔 你正在月球的背面
Neil, you are dark on the rock.
开始执行任务
Mission is a go.
你们有21分钟
We have 21 minutes.
阿波罗11号 你们还有13分45秒…
The Apollo 11, We have 13 minutes and 45 seconds.
我的天啊
My God.
好像是张巨大的金属面孔
It's some sort of giant metal face.
天啊…
Jesus.
控制中心 我们进入飞船了
Control, we are inside the ship.
船体受损严重
Extensive damage.
难以对飞船进行全面检查
Way too big to check the entire ship.
这里一片死寂 休斯顿
Everything's dead in here, Houston.
没有任何生命迹象
No signs of life anywhere.
这些东西巨大无比
These things are massive.
收到 你们的氧气还能维持7分钟
We copy. You've got seven minutes on your oxygen.
宇宙中并不只有我们 对吗？
We are not alone after all, are we?
没错 长官 并不只有我们
No, sir. We're not alone.
请讲 总统先生
Go ahead, Mr. President.
你们好 尼尔和巴兹 我正在给你们打电话
Hello, Neil and Buzz. I'm talking to you by telephone
来自白宫椭圆形办公室
from the Oval Room at the White House.
这绝对是一段将要载入史册的通话
And this certainly has to be the most historic telephone call ever made.
我难以表达对你们的自豪之情
I just can't tell you how proud we all are of you.
对每一位美国人 这都是此生中最为骄傲的一天
For every American, this has to be the proudest day of our lives.
因为你们的伟大壮举…
Because of what you have done...
我们已降落在海面上
We have splashdown.
太空成为了
the heavens have become a part
人类世界的一部分
of man 's world.
这宝贵的一刻
For one priceless moment
将会永远铭载人类史册
in the whole history of man
全世界的人们此刻心连心
all the people on this Earth are truly one.
为你们的壮举而感到骄傲
One in their pride in what you have done.
这鼓舞着我们要加倍努力
It inspires us to redouble our efforts
维护地球的和平与安宁
to bring peace and tranquility to Earth.
变  形  金  刚 月黑之时
我的英雄该醒醒啦
My hero needs to wake up.
那是什么？
What is that?
是你的新幸运兔
This is your new lucky bunny.
嗯 这是个美好的愿望 卡莉
It's a beautiful thought, Carly,
不过并不是兔子全身都带着好运
but I don't think it's the whole bunny that's lucky.
只有这一块地方
You see, it's just this section here.
只有兔脚这里才会带来好运
You see, it's just the rabbit foot that's lucky.
好吧 这只是个开运魔法
Well, it's just a good luck charm.
能让你积极向上起来
To help you think positive?
今天很重要
Today's important.
快点 起床吧
Come on, get up.
- 嘿 系那条领带比较帅 - 好
- Hey, wear that nice tie. - Yeah.
要我留午饭钱吗？
You need any money for lunch?
不 不用留午饭钱了
No, I don't need any money for lunch.
昨天的午饭钱还有点呢
I have money from yesterday's lunch.
你喜欢这样是吗？
You love it, don't you?
我是你包养的玩偶
I'm just your American boy toy.
是情人兼玩偶
A lover boy toy.
你知道这有多郁闷吗？ 我两次拯救世界
You know how demoralizing it is to have saved the world twice
居然还得低声下气地去找工作
and still be groveling for a job?
公众可不知道你拯救过世界 山姆
People don't know you saved the world, Sam.
但我知道 我相信你
I mean, I do. I believe you.
政府既然知情
The government knows.
就应该在华盛顿这里给我找份差事
I mean, they could hook me up with a job right here in D.C.
我应该去跟汽车人共事
I mean, I should be working with the Autobots,
否则就太不公平了
otherwise it's not fair.
拜托 他们已经供你上了大学
Come on, they paid for your college.
总统还给你颁发了英雄勋章呢
The President gave you a hero medal.
谢谢你 山姆 干得好
Thank you, man. Great job.
这可太酷了
That's the coolest thing that ever happened to me.
好吧 伙计们
All right, guys.
搞什么！
What the fuck!
我记得 那天好像也不是你最风光的时候
And, as I recall, that wasn't even the highlight of your day.
大使先生 请
Mr. Ambassador, here.
英国大使馆 你们是下一个
British Embassy, you're up next.
把它放进去 别动 看看都不行吗？
No, you don't wear it. See, you've gotta... The box.
放进盒子 我就是想戴戴
I couldn't, even if I wanted to.
把它放进盒子 好吗？
You're supposed to leave it in the box, right?
放进去别动 瞧这盒子真漂亮
You keep it in this. What a gorgeous box.
对 是我的勋章
Oh, yeah. My medal.
知道是谁给我的吗？
You know who gave that to me?
- 谁？ - POUTS
- Who? - POUTS.
美国总统
President of the United States.
宝贝 不是每个人都能找到工作的
Babe, it's hard for everybody to get a job.
我没有时间了 我爸妈下星期就要来这里了
I don't have time. You see, my parents are gonna be here in a week
他们开着房车在环游世界
on their road trip Partybus World Tour.
我爸来了之后 要是看到我没工作
If my dad gets here and I don't have a job,
肯定会赏我耳光的 我得行动了
he's gonna spank me. You know, it's go time for me.
那好吧 今晚我给你安排个工作
All right, tonight, I'll give you a job.
给我做一顿美妙的浪漫大餐
Romance me with a nice dinner
然后我再多给你一点小费
and maybe you can get that bonus.
- 真走运 - 把他弄出去
- Get lucky. - Get him out of here.
等等 不 不 不 不
Wait. No, no, no, no.
- 哦 他可真无礼！ - 她还不错
- Oh, he's gross! - She's good.
他们流落到了这里 得有人照顾他们
They're stranded here. Somebody's got to watch out for them.
昨天它还钻进了我的内衣抽屉
Yesterday, that one was in my underwear drawer.
研究一下嘛 顺便大饱眼福
Did research. Looking real good, too.
你还真打我啊！
No need to hit me.
你可不是个普通男朋友
You are not a normal boyfriend.
你爱的就是我这点
That's what you love about me.
- 小抱怨鬼 - 我还没说过爱这个字吧
- Crybaby. - We're not at the love word yet.
等你有能力分摊房租再说吧
Maybe a little bit closer when you're covering your half of the rent.
再见
Good-bye.
一下雨就害得我短路！
Frickin' shorting my circuits out here!
太没有人情味了！让我们住在小盒子里
It's inhumane, what it is! Make us live in a box
和阳台上的那畜生待在一块！把我当成动物看待！
on a balcony, right next to a beast! Like a common animal!
闭嘴 行吗？
Stop, okay?
你和你那丑哥们 未经允许不能进来
You and your creepy sidekick can't be in here without permission.
谁定的规矩？那个金发妞吗？
According to who? Miss Blondie Blonde?
起来 小狗狗！
Giddyup, little doggie!
- 嘿 聪明鬼 你怎么样啊？ - 还不错
- Yo, Brains, wassup?    - Doing good.
没意思 这集我看过了
Shit, I seen this one.
是斯巴克发疯的那集
It's the one where Spock goes nuts.
山姆 我真不知道该怎么跟那妞相处
You know, Sam, I don't know about moving in with this chick.
她要是像上一任那样甩了咱们可怎么办？
What if she dumps us like the last girl?
她凶巴巴的 我不喜欢她
She was mean. Didn't like her.
咱们现在可得同仇敌忾
Us guys got to stick together.
我们是一家人吶
We are family
我们是一家人
不 我们可不是一家人 你不过是外星难民
No, we are not family. You're a political refugee,
我好不容易才找了一个欣赏我的人
and I have finally found someone who appreciates me for me.
那你得告诉她 我们不是你的宠物
Well, you tell her that we're not your pets,
更不是你的玩具！
and we're not your toys!
好吧 我们是高等的天才外星种族
All right? We're an advanced, genius alien race
只想找个家
just looking for a home.
- 也许这不是个好主意 - 我觉得不该停
- Maybe it wasn't such a good idea. - Didn't have to stop.
拜托 他们还能怎样？ 拖走吗？
Come on. What're they going to do, tow it?
他在哪？
Where is he?
小山山！
Sammy!
- 别这样 这很搞笑！ - 山姆
- Come on, that's funny! - Sam.
我想死你们了
I missed you guys so much.
不想才怪呢 你觉得这身如何？
Sure, you did. What do you think?
- 瞧你们 - 可爱吧
- Look at that. - Cute.
- 看着很老 - 闭嘴
- You look old. - Stop it.
能看得出岁数来
Feel like I can see the end.
我喜欢你的小领带 我的准儿媳妇在哪？
I love your little tie. Hey, where's my girl?
- 我们漂亮的卡莉哪去了？ - 她上班去了 妈妈
- Where's my beautiful Carly? - She's at work, Ma.
她找了份新工作
She's got a new job.
我以为你们一周之后才来的
You guys said you were gonna be here in a week.
是21号 而不是11号 爹 记得吗？
The 21st, not the 11th, Dad, remember?
我们快马加鞭赶过来的
We just hauled ass in this thing.
- 一直跑到没油了 - 这大家伙跑得飞快
- We stopped for gas. - This thing. The love tub, it flies.
我们打扰你了没？比如说你的工作？
Are we keeping you from something? Like, say, your job?
嗯 上班时间到了 应该很着急吧
Well, it's about time. You had us worried.
我有几个面试要去
I have job interviews.
很好啊
That's good.
- 真糟糕 - 别说了
- That sucks. - Stop it.
别这么消极嘛 爸爸 这可是在华盛顿啊
You don't have to be so negative, Dad. You know, you're in D.C.
咱们一家人好不容易团聚了
You're here with your son and your family.
- 应该是高兴的时候 - 糟糕的是你居然没工作
- I mean, it's a good time. - It sucks that you don't have a job.
就是 有很多事可以做啊 对吧？
Yeah, but there's good things to do here, too, right?
对嘛？逛逛博物馆和纪念碑 好吗？
Right? Museums and monuments, okay?
- 晚上再见 - 我要把礼物收回
- I'll see you tonight. - I'm bagging the gift.
山姆 面试应该穿正式点的裤子
Sam, I think for an interview you should wear real pants.
你们应该天天都穿正式点的裤子
I think for life, you should wear real pants.
大黄蜂这是怎么了？
What happened to Bumblebee?
他去执行任务了 我只好拿这个当替补
He's off on his missions. I had to get this for backup.
- 连你的车也有工作 嗯？ - 别说了
- Your car has a job, huh? - Stop.
它能变成什么？
What does it change into?
什么也不会变 这就是件古董 妈
It doesn't change into anything. It's a collector's item, Ma.
便宜得很
I got it for a steal.
只需要保养一下就好 相信我
It just needs some work. Trust me.
不 这车挺可爱的 让我想起了大黄蜂
No, I think it's darling. It reminds me a lot of Bumblebee,
要是大黄蜂报废了大概就这个样子
if Bumblebee were a sad piece of shit.
来吧 我们送你去！
Come on, we'll give you a ride!
自从我们到来之后 我们的新家 地球
In the years since our arrival, our new home, Earth,
发生了许多变化
has seen much change.
能量检测仪保卫着每个城市
Energon detectors guard its cities now.
远程防御系统随时护卫领空
Long-range defense systems watch the skies.
非法核设施 中东
所以现在我们也协助盟友们解决人类间的冲突
So now we assist our allies in solving human conflicts,
阻止人类彼此伤害
to prevent mankind from bringing harm to itself.
是国防部长的车
The Defense Minister's car.
（立即放行！）
趴在地上 不许动！老实待着！
On the ground, per favore! And stay there!
我们组成秘密分队在全球各地执行各种任务
We work in secret teams on various missions around the globe.
并且与此同时
And all the while
我们也在寻找宿敌卷土重来的蛛丝马迹
we search for signs of our true enemies' return.
我是沃斯霍德 乌克兰能源部法律顾问
I am Voshkod, General Counsel with Ukrainian Department of Energy.
我国政府会否认
My government will officially deny
我们之间存在这次谈话
that we're having this conversation.
我们在一座废弃的核设施内有了意外发现
At one of our decommissioned facilities, a discovery was made,
恐怕是外星生物的痕迹
which I fear may be alien in nature.
那座核设施的名字叫 切尔诺贝利
The facility's name is Chernobyl.
切尔诺贝利核电站废墟
沃斯霍德先生
Mr. Voshkod.
自1986年起这里就成了一座空城
So, uninhabited since '86.
我听说两万年之内都不适宜人类居住？
I hear it won't be livable again for another 20,000 years?
至少两万年 乌克兰原本土壤肥沃
At least. Ukraine was the most fertile land.
那真是场悲剧
It's a tragedy.
这边请
This way.
做好准备！我们只能待60分钟
Gear up! We have 60 minutes on the ground.
注意各自的辐射量水平
Watch your radiation levels.
沃斯霍德先生 你的防护衣呢？
Mr. Voshkod, where's your protective gear?
你的防护衣在哪？
Where's your protective gear?
已经没必要了
It would not matter.
对我来说 死是迟早的事
For me, it's only a matter of time.
穿过这所学校
Through the school.
尤里会带你们下去 另外还有件事 上校
Yuri will take you below. And one other thing, Colonel.
别说出去 这里进行过能源实验
In private, there were some energy experiments.
待会儿再说
It can wait.
继续前进 跟紧点
Keep moving. Stay tight.
好 就是这里 我想是找到了
Okay, right here. I think I found it.
指挥官 我们有画面了
Optimus, we got a visual.
我们发现了一个东西被金属器械夹住了
Looks like the object's clamped in some kind of a metal harness.
这是什么？伙计们！
What's this? Guys!
这上面怎么有苏联太空竞赛计划的标志？
Why does this thing have Soviet space program markings on it?
史普尼克？（苏联发射的全球第一颗人造卫星）
Sputnik?
有能量读数 长官
Energon readings, sir.
非常强烈
It's strong.
在我们下面 来得很快
Below us. It's coming fast.
过来了 过来了！
Contact, contact!
到上面去！快走 快 快！
Get topside now! Move, move, move!
- 快走 快走！ - 准备！重武器准备！
- Let's go! - Weapons up! Heavy weapons up!
躲在我身后！
Stay behind me!
擎天柱！
Optimus!
快撤！
Fall back!
它绕着我们打转！
It's circling around us!
它在接近我们侧翼！
It's taking our flank!
准备重武器！
Get the heavy weapon!
擎天柱！
Optimus!
那是什么鬼东西？
What the hell was that thing?
那个
That
是震荡波
is Shockwave.
他怎么想要这个？
Why was he after this?
这不可能
It's impossible.
这是个引擎零件
This is an engine part
来自一艘失踪已久的汽车人飞船
from a long lost Autobot ship.
与你合作很愉快
Pleasure working with you.
要去面试了 真让人兴奋
Interviews. This is so exciting.
甜心 你要口香糖吗？
Honey, do you want some gum?
每次你一紧张 口气就很重
Your breath gets really gnarly when you're nervous.
- 维特维奇先生？ - 对 到此为止了
- Mr. Witwicky? - Yeah. Search is over.
我叫惠特利
I'm Mr. Whitley.
- 还有别人吗？ - 没有
- Is anybody else joining? - No.
没有？你要我坐到那里？
No? You want me to move right there?
- 我就坐到那里 - 最好别坐
- I'll move right there. - I'd prefer not.
好了吗？开始吧
Ready? Begin.
我是应届毕业生 主修地缘政治学 辅修文学专业
Graduated this year. Majored in geopolitics. Minor in tech studies.
兴趣在于政府与科技之间的
Very interested in government and technology,
如何进行对接和并存
how that's gonna intersect and co-exist.
要塑造未来
Shape the future.
当初干嘛要费劲地送他去读常春藤盟校？
Why did we bother sending him to an lvy college for?
都毕业三个月了还找不到工作？
Three months out of school and he can't find a job?
松笨先生…
Mr. Masuhisu...
我叫松本
Matsumoto.
- 松本 - 松笨
- Matsumoto. - Moto.
- 玛莎 可以叫你玛莎吗？ - 不 不可以
- Martha, can I call you Martha? - No, you may not.
好了 杰克 这世上有两种人
Okay, Jack, there's two types of people in this world.
一种是思想家 一种是实干家
There's think ers, there's doers.
一种是胜利者 一种是梦想者 还有一种是好哥们
There's winners, there's dreamers, and there's buddies.
谈谈你的缺点吧？
What about some weaknesses?
我没有…
I don't...
您长得很亲切
You have a very trustworthy face.
让我想起亚洲版的桑德斯上校（肯德基的创始人）
You remind me of like an Asian Colonel Sanders.
很值得我信任
A man I can trust.
他是00后
He's a millennial.
是说他们是 你懂的 迷惘的一代
That means they're the, you know, like lost generation.
联邦调查局为什么找你？
Why was the FBI looking for you?
为「什么」？
The what?
呃 联邦调查局 你正好提起那事了
Yeah, FBI. Good of you to flag that.
在你十四岁时应该干过外星人那种狂热的事
It was during all that alien craziness when you were 14.
他们对我很和气 立马就找到我
I mean, they were very kind to me, found me in a jiffy.
档案里的记录被删掉了
And that's all been expunged.
其实奥巴马给我发了奖章
Obama gave me a medal, actually.
不管怎样
I'm just saying.
公司招一个戴勋章的人总是件好事吧
It's always good to have a medal guy in the office, with a medal.
- 奥巴马颁发的？ - 对
- From Obama?     - Yeah.
这个公司里 大多数人都支持共和党 所以…
In this office, we're mostly Republicans, so...
我有点不舒服
I'm not feeling too good.
- 是吗？ - 嗯
- No?     - No.
干嘛不找个狗食盆再弄点拉肚子药呢？
Why don't you get a little dipping tray and dip the dog in Pepto?
肯定能管用的
That's a solution.
还有一场 我们得闪了
I got another one. We got to go.
- 快点 - 真的？
- Come on. - Really?
坐
Sit.
山姆·维特维奇先生 应届大学毕业生
Got myself a Mr. Sam Witwicky, recent college graduate.
之前工作经验 几乎为零
Previous experience, next to zero,
但是他却有本公司董事会的推荐信？
yet he has a recommend letter from our board?
这是怎么回事
WTF to that.
- 我认识你们公司董事吗？ - 这么说吧
- Do I know somebody on your board? - Here's the deal.
你也很了解我们 埃克塔系统公司
You know who we are. Accuretta Systems,
是航天电信业的龙头企业 去年盈利170亿
global leader in telecom, aerospace, 17 billion in profit last year.
我们的客户有国防部 国家航空航天局 喷气推进实验室等等
We contract for DARPA, NASA, JPL, you name it.
你表现得好 发展前途就非常广阔
You perform here, doors open for you anywhere.
毕业后的第一份工作很重要 孩子
First job out of college is critical, kid.
你要是没有走上正确的职业道路
You either take a step down the correct career path
后半辈子就掉到沟里去了
or you fall into a life-sucking abyss.
所以一切都取决于你如何回答我下面说的两个字
So it all depends on how you respond to my next two words.
打动我
Impress me.
- 现在？ - 打动我
- Now? - Impress me.
你让我毫无防备
You catch me off guard.
- 我不知从何说起  - 打动我
- I don't know where to begin. - Impress me.
我就是张大白纸 随便您怎么问
I'm an open book. Ask me any question you like.
- 那你就是很有野心 很强势… - 是的 先生
- So you're a go-getter, ramrod... - Yes, sir.
是个控制狂？
take-charge kind of guy?
我是个杀手 而且是冷血杀手
I'm a killer. A stone-cold killer.
那在控制欲方面呢？
So, take-charge guy?
掌控一切 维京人 野蛮凶狠 我人就这样
Take-charge, Viking, barbarian, of course, that's me.
嘿 您看着办吧
Pow! I'm here.
我们要的不是这种人
We are not looking for that here.
不要马屁精 不要小人 不要仆人 我…
No brown-nosing. No suck up. No toolery. I...
您好 布拉索斯先生
Yes, Mr. Brazos.
为什么尚塔尔会拿着一个像是红色的杯子
Why is Shontel using what appears to be a red cup
在红色楼层才能用的
from the red floor
- 而我们这层的主题是黄色呢？ - 我马上查
- when we are on the yellow floor? - I'm on it.
这是赤裸裸的视觉和灵魂上的背叛
It is a visual and, therefore, a visceral betrayal.
快给我办了！
Stop it!
真是个白痴
Such a dumbass.
真恶心！
Disgusting!
谢谢！
Thank you!
这里简直是无法无天
It's total anarchy around here.
你们电子邮件里说是招收行政人员？
The e-mail I read said administrative aide?
不 是收发员
Nope. Mailroom.
我还是走吧
I'm gonna go.
你知不知道有多少常春藤联盟的优秀毕业生
Do you have any idea how many lvy League Phi Beta Kappas
（斐陶斐：大学优等生荣誉学会）
- 来碰运气… - 先生 我已两次救过你的命 好吗？
- would kill to... - Mister, I saved your life twice. Okay?
我不能告诉你经过 时间 原因
I can't tell you how or when or why,
但我真的做过大事
but I have done shit that matters
而且我只是想再做点实事而已
and I'd just kind of like a job where I matter again.
所以谢了 即使不行也谢了 好吗？
So thank you, but no, thank you, okay?
你知道我怎么想的吗？你得先干这个才能干其它的
You know what I think? You want the job after this job.
孩子 你眼下只有这份差事可以做
But, son, this is the job that's standing in your way.
所以你一定会干得特别特别棒
And that's why you're gonna be so very, very good at it.
因为当我看到你时 就看到年轻时的自己
'Cause when I look at you, I see a younger me.
「巢穴」秘密总部 华盛顿特区
健康与人类服务部
所有在勤汽车人报到 十五分钟后开始训练
All arriving Autobots, in par, training and debriefing in 15 minutes.
恐龙 到23号车位报到
Dino, report to Bay 23.
横炮 到37号车位进行武器评估
Sideswipe, Bay 37 for weapons assessment.
议员先生 您兴许知道…
Senator, I suggest you remember that
当国航局需要资金时会找我
when the NSA wants funding, they call me.
当中情局想消灭某个目标时
When the CIA is gonna take out a target,
也得先获得我的许可
they ask first for my permission.
并且当总统想了解
And when the President wants to know
哪个国会参议员的政治把柄
which members of Congress are politically vulnerable
比方说 某些不为人知的罪行
in terms of, let's say, undiscovered criminal conduct,
也会打电话问我
I'm the number he dials.
美国政府声称正在调查这宗爆炸案
U.S. Agencies say they have been monitoring the blast.
但事实上假如这是一次秘密的军事打击行动
But if, in fact, this was a covert military strike,
- 没有国家声称对此事件负责 - 中情局一再追问我…
- no nation has claimed responsibility. - CIA is up my ass
关于这次中东袭击的幕后玄机
about this mystery raid in the Middle East.
所以你给我说清楚 这和你们有关吗？
So, it's time to come clean. Was your unit involved?
我不能确定 女士
I'm not sure, ma'am.
好了 伙计们 这是在示范如何射击霸天虎的头部
All right, guys. This is how you do a Decepticon head kill shot.
身为国家情报部门的局长
As Director of National Intelligence,
我希望你回答的时候动动脑子
I'm a really big fan of intelligent answers.
我真的没法确定
I can't really tell you definitively.
这些汽车人就像进入了青春期
These Autobots are like teenage kids.
他们动不动就偷偷溜出去了
They like to sneak out of the house every once in a while.
伦诺克斯上校 你到底是不是这里的指挥官？
Colonel Lennox, are you in command or are you not?
是的 女士 我是
Yes, ma'am, I am.
别叫我“女士” 我真是听够了“女士”
Stop with the "ma'am." Enough with the "ma'am."
我看起来像个“女士”吗？
Do I look like a "ma'am"?
是 女士 不是 女士 不是
No, ma'am. Yes, ma'am. Yes.
这枪可是我的完美杰作 铁皮
This gun is my perfect invention, Ironhide.
不错
Right.
太好了 他们来了！
Good, you're here!
我叫Q
Me name's Que.
我真希望你们能对他有所交代 我从没见过他如此生气
I do hope you have answers for him. I've never seen him so upset.
擎天柱 还记得夏洛特·梅琳吗？
Optimus, you remember Charlotte Mearing?
我们的国家情报部门局长？
Our Director of National Intelligence?
他情绪不太好
He's in a bad mood.
今天不想和任何人说话
He's not talking to anybody today.
这算什么意思 搞无声抗议吗？
What is this, the silent treatment?
- 那个我们知道 这是两码事 - 肯定不是
- We've seen that and this is not that. - Definitely not.
比那还严重
This is worse.
擎天柱！你总得有所表示吧！
Prime! Make something of yourself!
他都气疯了
He's pissed.
你骗了我们
You lied to us.
你们说过一切有关我们星球的情报都会共享
Everything humans know of our planet we were told had all been shared.
那这东西为什么会在人类的手里？
So why was this found in human possession?
我们起初也蒙在鼓里
We were in the dark on this also.
这事目前在第七区也只有局长知情
It was Director Only clearance at Sector 7 until now.
我的皮包
The bag.
- 哪个皮包？ - 爱马仕铂金包 绿色鸵鸟皮的那个！
- Which bag? - Hermes. Birkin. Green ostrich!
哦 我的天
Oh, my God.
这个秘密只有极少数人知道 目前在世的更是没几个
This is a secret few men knew, and fewer still remain alive.
容我向你介绍一下
Allow me to please introduce to you
两位国家航空航天局的行动组要员…
two of NASA's founding mission directors
以及宇航员巴兹·奥尔德林博士
and astronaut Dr. Buzz Aldrin,
他是当年首次登月的两位人类先驱之一
one of the first two men to step foot on the moon.
这位是擎天柱首领
Sir? Optimus Prime.
你我都曾遨游太空 很荣幸见到你
From a fellow space traveler, it's a true honor.
见到您我也很荣幸
The honor is mine.
我们在60年代的整个太空军备竞赛
Our entire space race of the 1960s, it appears,
全都是针对一件事
was in response to an event.
我们的宇航员调查了一艘坠毁的外星飞船
Our astronauts investigated a crashed alien ship.
但并未发现幸存者
No survivors onboard.
上头要求我们严守秘密
We were sworn to secrecy by our Commander in Chief.
这项任务绝不能对任何人透露
This was a mission you will never speak of.
明白 长官
I understand, sir.
在国航局总共有35个人知道这计划的真相
A total of 35 people knew the real plan at NASA.
苏联成功发射了无人登月探测器
Soviets managed to land unmanned probes.
他们大概是在那时取走了那根燃料棒
Somehow they must have picked up that fuel rod.
我相信苏联人发现了
We believe the Russians deduced
那燃料棒可以进行核裂变反应
that the rod was a fissionable fuel assembly,
并在切尔诺贝利核电站对其进行实验
believed they had it mastered, and tried to harness it at Chernobyl.
我们共组织了6次登月行动
We landed six missions in all.
拍下了数百幅照片 采集了样本
We took hundreds of photos and samples.
并将其永久封存
We locked them away forever,
之后探月计划便终止了
and the moon program was shut down.
你们搜查过防撞逃生舱吗？
Well, did you search the crash vault?
那艘飞船名叫「方舟」
The ship's name was the Ark.
我曾亲眼看着它逃离塞伯坦
I watched it escape Cybertron myself.
船上携带了一项汽车人的科技 本可以帮助我们赢得战争
It was carrying an Autobot technology which would have won us the war.
还有它的船长…
And its captain.
船长是谁？
Who was its captain?
伟大的御天敌 那项技术的发明者
The great Sentinel Prime, the technology's inventor.
他也是汽车人的领袖 我的前任
He was commander of the Autobots before me.
我必须找到方舟
It's imperative that I find it
而且抢在霸天虎获悉它的方位之前
before the Decepticons learn of its location.
我们汽车人的宇宙飞船有能力飞往月球
Our Autobot spacecraft has the ability to get there.
所以 你们必须祈祷这还来得及
And you must pray it's in time.
嗨 我找卡莉·斯宾塞
Hi. I'm here to see Carly Spencer.
卡莉！
Carly!
失陪一下
Excuse me.
- 你找到工作了？ - 简直不可思议
- You got the job? - This is crazy.
- 你真的找到了？ - 是的
- You really got it? - Yes.
看 我怎么说的来的？ 兔子给你好运气
See, what did I tell you? It's the bunny.
你也太客气了
You are so welcome.
- 是不是更爱我了？ - 好感度上升了点
- Do you like me more? - A little bit, yeah.
你只说你是他的助理馆长
You said you were his assistant curator,
你没说过这家伙拥有这么个宝贝啊
you didn't say the guy owns Space Mountain.
是吧 这里很漂亮吧？
I know. Isn't it beautiful in here?
而且我老板也是个超酷的家伙
And he's the coolest guy. Ever.
- 是吗？ - 是的
- Yeah?    - Yeah.
山姆
Sam.
迪伦·古尔德
Dylan Gould.
嘿 幸会
Hey. A pleasure to meet you.
幸会 卡莉经常向我提起你
Pleasure meeting you. Carly's told me a lot about you.
呃 她也常跟我提起您 这里真的挺漂亮
Well, vice versa. It's a beautiful building you got.
像进取号星舰（《星际旅行》）的场景
It's like the Starship Enterprise in here.
过奖 这里也漏雨
Thank you very much. It leaks.
在卡莉来帮忙打理之前
Before Carly came to help run the collection,
这整个场馆还是一团糟呢
it was just a complete mess.
但是现在装修工作总算重回正轨了
But now, the restorations are back on track.
我们要去今年的圆石滩巡展
We're going to Pebble Beach this year,
再赢一座奖杯回来
and we're gonna get a trophy for that stand right there.
你知道为什么吗？因为眼前这位小美女
You know why? Because this woman right here
- 就是我的秘密武器 - 是的
- is my secret weapon. - Okay.
古尔德先生 别这样 您过奖了 我只是负责组织工作
Mr. Gould, please, you exaggerate. All I've done is get you organized.
哦 你的功劳可多得多呢 我的公爵夫人
You've done much more than that, my Duchess.
都开始用昵称了 有意思
Nicknames, that's fun.
没错 公爵夫人
Yeah. The Duchess.
她人见人爱
She's adorable.
我把她从英国大使馆挖过来时
You know, when I stole her away from the British Embassy,
对她说 治国有何难？
I said, "It's easy to manage a country.
还不如来管理无价的艺术收藏品
"Try managing a priceless collection of art."
看看这辆1939年出厂的德拉哈耶-165敞篷跑车
Tak e a look at this 1939 Delahaye 165 Cabriolet.
法国人设计的
Designed by a Frenchman.
瞧瞧她的曲线 如此优雅 美丽
Look at the curves. Elegant, isn't it? Beautiful.
性感
Sensual.
如同窈窕淑女的曲线
Built to evoke the body of the ideal woman.
跟我来
Come on.
我父亲只靠一张破烂书桌和一个梦想
My dad had a $ 10 desk and a dream,
就建立了一个商业帝国
and he built it into an empire.
哇
Wow.
我们现在是全美最大的会计事务所
We're the largest accounting firm in the U.S.
他去世之后我从创投部门开始
I started up the venture side after he passed.
投资未来
Invest in the future.
试着把赌注压到获胜者的那一方
Try and bet on the winners.
而收集名车能帮助我在赌局中保持理智
See, collecting cars helps me keep my sanity.
看起来不错
You guys look great.
那天确实不错 古尔德先生
That was a great day, Mr. Gould.
- 我没见过这张 - 我也没看过呢
- I haven't seen that one. - No. Me, neither.
牛仔裤太紧了
Jeans are tight.
我们走 我们走 你都看见了？
Here we go. Here we go. You see that?
又以车取人了？
Judgment. Judging a man by his car?
他以车取人的时候 你居然无动于衷？
And you're gonna wave at him while he's judging me?
你怎么啦？ 他是我老板吶
What's with you? He's my boss.
这份工作提供我们的食物和租金
This job pays for our food, our rent.
行 我全明白了
No, I totally understand.
我是无所谓 我饿不着
I'm totally fine. I get it. I'm well fed.
知道吗？我不再是你的男孩玩具了
And guess what? I'm not your boy toy anymore.
我也穿正装了 看见没？
I got my big boy pants on. You see them?
请上车 谢谢 公爵夫人
In the car. Thank you, Duchess.
哦 天啊 他对你构成威胁了吗？
Oh, my God. Are you threatened by him?
威胁？我怕他什么？怕他有钱？有权？长得帅？
Threatened? What am I threatened by? His money? His power? His good looks?
全都是浮云 记好了！
None of the above. Check!
天啊！你吃醋的样子还真性感
God! Your temper tantrums are so sexy.
上车吧 拜托了
Get in the car, please.
山姆 他又不是第一个对我笑的男人
Sam, he's hardly the first man to ever smile at me.
- 我自有分寸    - 等等 等等
- I think I can handle it. - Hold on, hold on.
可你也冲他笑了 别说你没笑 好吗？
It's the smiling back part that gets me. Okay?
那我不笑了 以后不朝他笑了 我发誓
No more smiles. Never again. I promise.
这话我爱听
That works for me.
别急 别急！那样可发动不了
Easy! Easy! You're not gonna get it started that way.
我是在做准备 我只完成了32％的修复
Well, I was just getting it ready. I'm about 32% done with my restoration.
一些镀铬零件 加上扰流板就搞定了
Some chrome work, put a spoiler on the back. Done deal.
卡莉一直在说你找工作很辛苦
You know, Carly's been telling me you've been struggling job-wise.
所以让你知道
Just so you know,
我也是埃克塔系统公司的董事
I'm on the board for Accuretta Systems,
我跟他们打了个招呼
and I put in a call for you.
这事就我们俩知道就行了 好吗？
Let's keep it between us, okay?
她对你太好了
She's so proud of you.
你真是个幸运儿
You're a lucky man.
苍耳号 接近月球静海基地
Xanthium approaching Tranquility Base.
这里是休斯顿 苍耳号 准备降落
Here's Houston, you're a go Xanthium. You're a go for landing.
阿姆斯特朗 祝你们行动顺利
Armstrong, having a good day.
铁皮 我们走
Ratchet, let's roll.
他们把传感器打开了吗
Did they get that mag cap on?
通讯收到
Copy contact.
我们正在进入方舟号
We're entering the Ark.
他的能量指数很微弱
His levels are faint.
他把自己锁起来以保护那些能量柱
He locked himself away to guard the pillars.
御天敌
Sentinel.
欢迎你回家 老朋友
You're coming home, old friend.
威震天万岁
All hail Megatron.
是主人！主人回来了！
My master! Yes, my master! Yes!
别这么贪吃 我脆弱的小宝贝们
Don't be greedy, my fragile ones.
您气色很不好 主人
My poor master.
看到您如此虚弱 真是让我心痛不已
How it pains me to see you so wounded, so weak.
少来那套奉承话！
Spare me, you gaseous sycophant!
之前怎么教训你的来的？ 少说废话
You know what you are told, which is nothing.
威震天陛下 声波向您报告
Soundwave reporting, Lord Megatron.
你的小刺客带来了什么新消息？
And what news from your little assassin?
汽车人上钩了
Autobots have taken the bait!
他们找到了方舟 带走了上面的东西
They've discovered the Ark and returned with its cargo.
你跟踪那飞船一直到月球 干得漂亮
You did me great honor tracking that ship to the moon.
你的人类合作伙伴已经物尽其用 声波
Your human collaborators have served their purpose, Soundwave.
该让他们闭嘴了
It's time to eliminate loose ends.
激光鸟 杀光他们
Laserbeak, kill them all.
乐意之至
With pleasure.
你爸爸在家吗？
Is your daddy home?
- “于是玛德琳说…” - 玛德琳！
- "Then Madeline said..." - Madeline!
你好 妈妈
Hello, Mom.
救命！
Help!
从我家滚出去！
Get out of the house!
- 你来我家干什么？ - 只是路过回访
- What are you doing in my house? - Just visiting.
航太系统公司
你这是什么爆乳装打扮？
What is this hoochie-mama outfit?
姐穿什么关你屁事？（西班牙语）
不 这里是航天系统部！我们不允许那样的穿着！
No, this is the aerospace division! We do not allow that here!
新来的！你看到了吗？崩溃的拉丁女人就是这样
New guy! You see that? That's a Latin meltdown, okay?
在我办公室里你要是穿着爆乳装 就会被炒鱿鱼
You ever show up in my office with a hoochie-mama outfit, you're fired.
明白了吗？
You got that?
你准备跟这小车一起待上两年半 好吧？
Okay, you're gonna be on this cart for two-and-a-half years, okay?
我要你享受它 爱着它 并给它取名
I want you to live it, love it and name it.
在我这里没有捷径可走 我要求很严 明白吗？
There's no ladder climbing in my office. I run a tight ship. Okay?
- 是 先生 - 去工作！
- Yes, sir. - Move!
上次提到的那份报告 我找到了
I found that paper I was telling you about.
- 你在看什么？ - 闭嘴！
- What are we looking at? - Shut up!
再对我这样 我就揍你！
You do that to me again, and I'll kick your ass!
嗨 宝贝
Hi, angel.
- 你好吗？ - 不错
- How are you? - Good.
我到市中心开会 顺便来看看你不妨碍吧？
I had a meeting downtown. Was it okay for me to stop by?
不知道 这本500页的员工行为手册
I don't know. My 500-page employee conduct manual
可并不是翻页器
isn't exactly a page turner.
看起来很沉闷
This is great.
汽车人在四处拯救世界 而我却在整理这些信件
Yeah, Autobots are off saving the world, and I have organized four binders.
瞧这工作多理想 跟我来
I'm living the dream. Come on.
外人不许随便进出
Visitor violation.
- 你还好吗？ - 当然
- You okay? - Absolutely.
我在排队
I'm next.
听好 这星期六 迪伦要在他家里搞聚会
Listen. Saturday. Dylan's throwing a party at his house.
虽然是项工作 但他也邀请了你
It's a work thing, but he's invited you, too.
是吗？
Did he?
到时可别嘲笑我的冷笑话
I want you to come and laugh at my bad jokes.
这对我很重要 知道吗？
It would really mean a lot to me, okay?
那我去 你怎么来这儿的？
I'd love to go. How'd you get over here?
- 开车 - 你明明没有车
- Car. - You don't have a car.
- 现在有了 - 什么 你中大奖了？
- Yes, I do. - What, did you win it in a raffle?
他给了我一辆
He gave me one.
他给了你一辆车？
He gave you a car?
嗯 就算是员工福利吧
Yeah, I think it was a work perk.
员工福利
A work perk.
他给了你辆什么车？
What kind of car did he give you?
一辆梅赛德斯SLS-AMG
A Mercedes SLS AMG.
引擎声音很低沉
Really throaty engine.
梅赛德斯-奔驰 SLS
Mercedes-Benz SLS
- 具有惊人的性能… - 你开着它来的？
- combines breathtaking performance.... - You drove this here?
这车价值20万美元
That's a $200, 000 car.
我知道
I know.
你知道我得赚多久钱才能买得起这车吗？
You know how long it would take me to afford a car like this?
- 很久吗？ - 是的 大约53年
- A long time? - Yeah, like 53 years.
他说了这算是员工福利了
He said it was for both of us.
知道我们该怎么做吗？ 应该卖了它买房子
Then what we should do is, we should sell it and buy a house.
你很沮丧 我知道
You're frustrated, I know.
我也经历过
I've been there.
这就叫做先苦后甜
It's called paying your dues.
好日子总会来的
Good things will happen.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我需要有人牺牲午饭时间来做文件归档
I need some lunch time filing done, stat.
谁愿意让布鲁斯·布拉索斯多加点印象分？
Who would like to score some Bruce Brazos points?
布鲁斯 你找到人了
Bruce, you found your guy.
维特维奇
Witwicky!
本公司的栋梁之才
The man who makes this company run.
这位是谁啊？
Now, who have we here?
是一个妹妹 脸书网友 还是推特粉丝？
Is it a sister, Facebook friend, Twitter tweeter?
- 卡莉 这是布鲁斯 布鲁斯 - 嗨
- Carly, this is Bruce. Bruce. - Hi.
我是他的女友 幸会 山姆说得没错
I'm his girlfriend. A pleasure to meet you. Sam was right.
您的发型真的很帅
You really do have a smashing head of hair.
嗯 谢谢你
Well, thank you.
- 山姆 我得走了 - 好
- Sam, I got to run. - Yeah.
给你 送你的礼物
Here, your present.
是你最喜欢的颜色
Your favorite color.
- 见到您很高兴 布拉索斯先生 - 我也是
- Nice to meet you, Mr. Brazos. - And you.
再见 小伙子们
See you, boys.
活页夹的事搞得我很不爽 杰瑞
I'm still stewing about that binder incident, Jerry.
能让我喝完舒化奶吗 唐尼？
May I finish my Shuhua milk, Donny?
我才不在乎你的外国牛奶
I don't care about your exotic milk.
我说的是尊重！
I care about respect!
我知道你是谁！
I know who you are!
维特维奇！维特维奇！
Witwicky! Witwicky!
- 我在和你说话！ - 借过 谢谢你
- I'm talking to you! - Excuse me. Thank you.
不 不 慢一点 小老虎
Slow down, tiger.
你在六张不同照片的背景里出现
You showed up in the background of six different photos,
和外星人一起去过两个大陆
two continents, with aliens.
而且那个在埃及的人就是你
That was you in Egypt,
对吧？
right?
因为你认识那些外星人
Because you know the aliens.
回头见！
See you!
还我外套！
Give me my jacket!
我姓王 深王 深王
I'm Wang. Deep Wang. Deep Wang.
你不明白吗 「深喉」探员
You're not getting it. Deep Throat.
水门事件？ 我告诉你代号…
Watergate? I'm talking code to you...
该死的
Damn it.
他们在监视监听
They watch and listen.
我不能去找政府 但是你可以！
I can't go to the government, but you can!
因为要出事了 孩子！代号是「平克」「平克-佛洛伊德」的「平克」！
Because shit's going down, son! It is Code Pink, as in Floyd!
暗面！你知道为什么1972年后就没人去那里了吗？
Dark Side! Why do you think no one's been up there since 1972?
你讲的是英语 但是却是听不懂的英语
I know you're speaking English, it's just a very strange English.
因此我…
That's why I'm not...
不要 我会打你的
Don't. I'm gonna hit you.
别打了 你会感谢我的
I'm gonna hit you right back, son.
这是我的声明书
It's my manifesto.
他们要干掉我们！
They're whacking us out,
干掉每个知道暗面内情的人…
everyone who knows what's on the dark...
你的外星朋友们有危险 他们靠你拯救了
Your alien friends are in danger, you know, the good ones. It's up to you.
下来
Calm down.
放松 山姆
Easy, Sam!
你看什么看？
What are you looking at?
哼 你这老狗
Yo, dawg.
看我的屎吗？你为谁工作？
Are you up in my shit? Who are you working for?
看谁能瞪过谁
Staredown, you and me.
看来我赢了
Guess I won.
月球… 清单
Moon satellites.
更多被搁置的计划
The Russian space program.
专家身亡
Experts dead.
太空计划结束
Space program ends.
暗面… 月之暗面
Dark side... Dark side of the moon.
看看我在洗手间找到了什么 是你的吗？
Look what I found outside the bathroom. Is it yours?
- 去处理好这些东西 - 是的 先生
- Deal with this.   - Yes, sir.
你让我做的事情我都做了！
I did everything you want!
我想我们该好好谈谈 因为有些事情…
I really think we should talk, 'cause some of the stuff...
哇 要先敲门
Whoa! Knock first!
没看到我正忙着吗！
Can't you see I'm busy?
你是谁 你是谁？
Who are you? Who are you?
你刚才在隔间里跨在我身上
You straddled me in the stall.
我这辈子头回遇上这种事 我忘不了的
That's happened to me once in this life. I wouldn't forget it.
在厕所的隔间里
From the bathroom stall.
你把你的东西掏了出来
You took your package out.
我们不是同性恋 好吗？
We are not boyfriends, okay?
我打个电话就可以把你炒掉
One phone call from me and I'll have you fired.
没错 我会的 同性恋！
Yes, I will, Gaylord!
你还好吧？
Are you okay?
痔疮犯了！
Hemorrhoids!
我该回来吗？ 我该什么时候再过来？
Should I come back? When should I come back?
等你学会礼貌再来！
Come back when you learn some manners!
我不认识他！我什么都没说！
I don't know him! I would never say anything!
好吧 好吧！是我破坏了测图卫星
Okay, okay! I sabotaged the mapping satellite,
就像我承诺过的
just like I promised,
我能在程序中设一个盲点作为奖励
I can put a blind spot in the program as a bonus.
你还要我干些什么？
What more do you want from me?
杰瑞 我最喜欢你
Jerry, you are my favorite.
你让我干什么都行
I'll do whatever you want me to do.
我知道 但我的主人要求我…
I know, but my superiors need me to...
拜托 你没必要… 自杀
Please, you don't have to... suicide you.
你对维特维奇说了些什么？
What did you say to Witwicky?
去你的吧
Shit!
贱货 想尝尝鸡肉大餐吗？
Who wants some chick en dinner now, bitch?
今天真的有人把我姓王的惹毛了
'Cause somebody messed with the wrong Wang today!
来吧！你想要杀我吗？
Come on! You want some of me?
我不想再听到查克没完没了的唠叨！
I don't need any more didactic lectures from Chuck.
天啊！
Jesus!
通知法律部
Get legal.
那是杰瑞！
That's Jerry!
大家注意 没错 有同事死了
Come on, people. Yes, a workmate died,
但是光看窗外是不会令他复活的
but looking out the window is not going to bring him back.
他得了抑郁症
The man was depressed.
别拍照！
Don't take a picture!
你们可以一直看 但他不会站起来
You can keep watching him, but he's not getting up.
你们都看过“ 汉普蒂邓普蒂” 好吗？
You all read "Humpty Dumpty." Okay?
（童谣中从墙上摔下跌得粉碎的蛋形矮胖子）
维特维奇
Witwicky.
我去对付媒体 你来打扫现场
I'm spearheading the press. You clean up.
老王摔的到处都是 酒吧里有
Wang is everywhere. He is in the bistro.
树林里有 栏杆上也有
He's in the bamboo. He's on the balustrade.
看到下面的人行道了吗？
You see the sidewalk down there? Man!
帮他打包 去掉他停车位上的名字
Box up his personals. Get his name off his parking space.
嘿 我们什么时候又买了一台影印机？
Hey, when did we get a new copier?
听着 我不会说出刚才看到的事情
Listen, I'm not gonna say anything about what I saw.
你和谁共用一间厕所完全是你个人的事
Who you share a toilet stall with is totally your business.
这一定是日货
This is exceedingly Japanese.
日货使用从来不会简单化 不是吗？
They never make it easy, do they?
- 你怎么了？ - 出大事了 卡莉 好吗？
- What is with you? - This is the real deal, Carly, okay?
我需要你保持冷静
I need you to stay composed.
这是真事 我等一下会给你解释
It's real life. I'll explain it to you later.
我们遇到了紧急情况 快把伦诺克斯上校找来
We've got an emergency. You gotta get Colonel Lennox out here.
我指的是霸天虎 霸天虎又杀回来了
I'm reporting a Decepticon. The Decepticons are back.
你们得立即开门
You gotta open that gate right now.
冷静点 先生 这里是公共健康与社会福利部
Easy, sir. This is Health and Human Services.
是啊 还拿着M-4步枪？
Right. Packing M4s?
你们保护什么 结肠瘘袋？
What are you protecting, colostomy bags?
便盆？ 止咳糖浆？
Bedpans? Throat lozenges?
你们的帽子从哪里来的 护理学校？
Where'd you get that hat from, nursing school?
难道说你们是在保卫护士和脚气药粉？真有趣
So, you're nurses and foot-powder protectors? Fantastic.
- 宝贝 - 在呢
- Babe. - Yes.
我认为我们没有走错
I don't think we're in the right place.
我们找对地方了
We are in the right place.
我们找的就是这里 我要和擎天柱讲话
We're in the right place and I'm gonna talk to Optimus right now.
- 马上带我去见擎天柱 - 先生
- You're gonna get Optimus out here. - Sir.
先生 我想你来错地方了
Sir, you got the wrong building.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
“霸天虎杀回来了” 你们哪句话没听懂？
What part of "Decepticons are back" do you not understand?
你！最好放明白点！
Yo! You being a smartass?
别碰我的车！ 这可是古董！
Do not hit my car! It's a collector's item!
我不会这么做
I wouldn't do that.
你疯了！
You're crazy!
发现了外星能量讯号！
We got an Energon reading!
讯号来自车内！
We've got aliens in the vehicle!
动一下就打死你！出来！出来！
You move, you're dead! Out! Out!
车里发现异形体！
Got aliens in the vehicle!
- 不许动！出来！ - 我们不动！
- Freeze! Get out! - We're freezing!
你们…
Are you...
你们在开玩笑吗？
Are you kidding me?
山姆 他们有枪！
Sam, they've got guns!
- 我抓住他了 走！ - 大黄蜂！你在吗？
- I got him. Go! - Bee! Is Bee in there?
好吧 好吧！
Okay, all right!
你们就是这样对待汽车人吗？都是自己人
This how you treat Autobots? We're on the same team.
祝你将来在7-11便利店打工愉快 白痴
Yeah, enjoy your next job at 7-Eleven, dickhead.
- 说得没错 - 浑球
- That's right. - A-hole.
你的车呢？
How's your car now?
那才是我的车
That's my car.
过来
Come here.
过来！
Come here!
说吧… 山姆
Come on. Sam.
你怎么回事？
What is your deal?
我知道你们的秘密行动很重要
I know your black ops stuff is important to you.
我并没有轻视 也不想让你内疚
I'm not trying to diminish it or guilt-trip you or anything,
可我再也没见过你的面
I just never see you anymore.
你就不能回车库待一晚上吗？
You can't come to the garage and just hang out one night?
山姆 这话让我好难过
Sam. That makes me feel bad.
是的 我希望你感到难过 你应该感到难过
I hope you feel bad. You should feel bad.
看看我现在开的这辆破车
Look at the jalopy I'm driving now.
我每天都感到难过
I feel bad every single day.
你 你们两个都过来 伦诺克斯要见你们
Yo, let's go, both of you. Lennox wants to see you.
什么 你们不再扣留我们了？
What, we not good enough for you anymore?
对不起 他们过于粗暴了
I'm sorry, babe. They were very rude, all right?
你得给我去修车 你以为会没事？
And you're fixing my car. You don't think so?
举起你的手来 如果出现一个飞行变态忍者影印机
Raise your hand if you had a flying psycho-ninja copier
尽力想杀死你！
trying to kill you today!
这是我的指节铜环
Those are my brass knuckles.
那是我的脚环 也需要我脱掉吗？
That's my anklet. Do I have to take that off, too?
脚趾环呢？
And my toe rings?
所有NEST的官员撤离本层
All NEST officials clear the floor.
距离接触行动还有10分钟
We have 10 minutes until attempted contact.
我们获得了五件仪器
We've taken possession of the five devices
它们被藏在御天敌的飞船里
that were hidden in the ship with Sentinel Prime.
它们都是某种汽车人科技的原型机
They're some kind of prototype Autobot technology.
他们说御天敌相当于汽车人的爱因斯坦
They say Sentinel was the Einstein of his civilization,
所以我们要锁好这些东西
so we're gonna keep these locked up
直到我们搞清它们的用处
until we know what we're dealing with.
现在任何人不得入内 任何人
Right now, no one gets access. No one.
这个姓王的家伙认出了我 他让我来警告你们
This Wang guy recognized me. He told me to warn you.
他提到了月球的背面
He was talking about the dark side of the moon,
- 然后他们杀了他 - 等一下
- then they killed him. - Wait a minute.
- 你说月球？ - 是的 月球背面
- He mentioned the moon? - Yeah, dark side of the moon.
霸天虎为什么要暗杀人类？
But why would Decepticons want to kill humans?
我觉得他们的对手应该是汽车人
I thought their war was with the Autobots.
当时他做了头一份初期评定科学报告
And that is when he made his first quick-look science report.
那是我想要的…
That's what we want...
这小妞是谁？
Who's the chick? Okay.
打扰了 伦诺克斯上校
Excuse me! Colonel Lennox?
梅琳局长 这位是山姆·维特维奇…
Director Mearing, this is Sam Witwicky...
我认识他 上校
I know his name, Colonel.
我想知道谁给了他许可？
I wanna know who gave him clearance?
谁给了我许可？ 擎天柱行不行？
Who gave me clearance? How about Optimus Prime,
当时他跑到我们那里寻找我家
when he touched down in suburbia looking for my house?
这位是国家情报处局长
This is the National Intelligence Director.
如果你不知道的话…
In case you...
藐视联邦官员？
Disrespecting a federal officer?
这就够你受的了 她是谁？
Maybe that'll get you somewhere. Who's she?
她是我女友
She's my girlfriend.
这算什么 约会吗？
What is this, like, a date?
汽车人的事她全知道 她知道大黄蜂
She knows all about the Autobots, okay? She knows Bumblebee.
她来自一个军人家庭 我可以为她担保
And she comes from a military family. I can vouch for her.
好吧 我有主意了 我们还是谈谈正事吧？
Hey, I have an idea. How about we get back to the important topics,
比如 我今天差点就被一个霸天虎砍了头
like the fact that I almost had my face cut off by a Decepticon?
做为一名纳税人 我想我可以抗议 事实上…
As a taxpayer, I'd like to lodge a complaint, as a matter of fact.
好吧 听着 好吗？
Okay, listen, all right?
山姆办公室的一名软件工程师今天被暗杀了
One of the software engineers at Sam's office was murdered today.
他参与过国家航空航天局的探月项目
He was involved in NASA's lunar mapping probe.
情况是这样 伦诺克斯上校
Here's the thing, Colonel Lennox.
我们不能把国家安全交付给这些年轻人
We cannot entrust national security to teenagers
除非我违反政策文件 能让这种事发生吗？
unless I missed a policy paper. Are we doing that now?
不能 很好
No. Good.
我不在乎你是谁
I don't care who you are.
如果你敢泄露你所看到的一切
If you breathe a word of what you see in here,
你将会因叛国罪而坐牢
you will do time for treason.
明白我的话吗？
Do you understand me?
我听从汽车人的命令 我认识他们 但不认识你
I'll take my orders from the Autobots. I know them. I don't know you.
你会认识的
You will.
御天敌
Sentinel Prime.
他靠能量生存 但现在没能量了
These things run on Energon, and he's out of it.
他现在处于休眠状态
He's in a sort of a sleep mode.
我们开始吧
Let us begin.
这就是伟大的领导模块
That's the great Matrix of Leadership.
宇宙中只有它才能给变形金刚的火种补充能量
He holds the only thing in the universe that can repower a Transformer's spark.
难以置信
This is incredible.
御天敌
Sentinel Prime,
请你醒来吧
we bid you return.
（复仇）
住手别开火！
Hold your fire!
住手！御天敌！
Stop! Sentinel!
是我 擎天柱！
It is I, Optimus Prime!
一切都好 你很安全
It is all right. You are safe.
没什么可害怕的
There is nothing to fear.
我们都在这里
We are here.
你到家了 御天敌
You are home, Sentinel.
战争呢？ 战争！
The war... The war!
战争失败了
The war was lost.
塞伯坦成了不毛之地
Cybertron is now but a barren wasteland.
我们逃难到了地球
We have taken refuge here, on planet Earth.
这里的人类是我们的盟友
Its human race is our ally.
我的飞船 我们冲破战火而来
My ship. We came under fire.
能量柱 能量柱在哪里？
The pillars. Where are the pillars?
你救出了5根 包括主控柱
You saved five of them, including the control pillar.
只有5根？
Only five?
我们曾经有数百根
We once had hundreds!
对不起 先生们
Excuse me, gentlemen.
我可以问一下 你们在开发的是什么技术？
May I ask, what is this technology you're looking for?
它具有重塑宇宙的能力
It is the ability to reshape the universe.
能量柱结合在一起就可以形成太空桥
Together the pillars form a space bridge.
是我设计的 只有我一个人才能操作
I designed, and I alone, can control it.
它违背了你们的物理定律
It defies your laws of physics
能够超时空传送物质
to transport matter through time and space.
你们说的是一种远程传送装置 对吧？
You're talking about a teleportation device, aren't you?
是的 可以传送资源、难民
Yes, for resources, for refugees.
难民或者士兵 武器 甚至炸弹！
Refugees, or troops of soldiers, weapons, maybe bombs!
是种瞬时打击的手段！这就是它的军事用途 对吧？
A means of an instant strike! That's its military function, isn't it?
这是我们的技术 必须拿回来
It is our technology and it must be returned.
对 得人类同意才行
Yes. If humans say so.
你们不能随便把大规模杀伤性武器带入我们的大气层！
You can't just bring weapons of mass destruction into our atmosphere!
至少要先申报海关！
You kind of have to clear customs first!
还要走一些官方手续
A little formality called paperwork
这就是我们和动物之间的区别
kind of separates us from the animals.
你如果能够充分尊重我
I will overlook your condescending tone
我就原谅你的趾高气昂
if you heed the gravity of mine.
霸天虎不知道太空桥在这里
The Decepticons must never know the space bridge is here.
一旦太空桥落入他们手中
For in their hands,
那就是你们的世界末日
it would mean the end of your world.
都是我的文件
"Total Nightmare" file.
调查行动开始了
So, the investigation is open.
我们会派探员去你的办公室
We've sent agents to your office.
现在 我们打算派汽车人护送你们回家
And, for the time being, we're gonna send you home with Autobot protection.
我应该和谁谈
Who do I need to speak to
才能让你们明白我能帮上忙 能尽一份力呢？
to get you guys to understand that I can help, that I can contribute?
嘿 我们都能帮忙 你告诉我你知道的
Hey, we can all help. Want to tell you what I know?
我告诉你关于太阳系吧 那些好玩的星球晃来晃去
I could tell you about the solar system, all the fun planets to hang out in.
拜托从我桌子上下去
Get off my desk, please.
你居然掏枪？现在我不想帮你了 她生气了
You pulling out guns? I can't help you out now. She angry.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
你们想要我干什么？让我回家去？
What do you envision for me? I go home now?
回去工作吗？玩影印机是吗？
I go back to work? I make copies? I mean...
这个组织的成员都是些资深的探员
This is a unit for veteran intelligence officers
和特种部队
and Special Forces,
可不是有特殊汽车的男孩来的地方
not for boys who once owned special cars.
你有点刻薄了吧 女士？
That's a bit harsh, isn't it, ma'am?
不要叫我「女士」 我不是「女士」
Don't call me ma'am. I'm not a ma'am.
你不是女的吗？
Well, you're a woman, aren't you?
那么 这些是你的？
So, are those yours?
是的 中情局发的
Yeah. CIA.
我之所以问是因为我也有奖章
I only ask 'cause I also have a medal,
总统发的
from the President.
没错 好 那我就不兜圈子了 好吧？
Yeah. Great. So, it's not that complicated, right?
没有我同意 谁都不能和汽车人合作
No one gets to work with the Autobots unless I approve it.
你破坏了我的指挥程序
You're breaking my chain of command.
好吧 我们走 你能做的都做了
Come on, let's go. You've done what you came for.
老实说 小伙子 我感谢你做的一切
With all due respect, young man, I appreciate what you did.
但你不是军人
But you're not a soldier.
你只是个送信的 永远都是
You're a messenger. You've always been a messenger.
他是个英雄
He's a hero.
大黄蜂 你去坐货运电梯 我们楼上见
Bee, you take the freight elevator. I'll see you up there.
这真是鬼扯 那个女人把我们踢出来了
This blows. That lady officially kicked us out.
没错 证人保护程序烂透了
Yeah. Witness Protection Program sucks.
说得不错 但有大黄蜂在至少我们更安全了
Yeah, but we're a whole lot safer with big yellow and his cannons.
那条狗可保护不了咱们
That dog can't protect crap.
大黄蜂
Bee?
你想出去？
You miss hanging out?
是啊 我也想
Yeah, me, too.
那个女人 她说我是个送信的
That woman, she called me a messenger.
你们能相信吗？忙了半天 我只是个送信的
Can you believe that? After everything I've done, I'm a messenger.
哦 我相信你山姆 说实话我们也有同感
I believe it. I tell you, Sammy, we feel the same way.
这个星球上的人都不懂得尊重别人
The disrespect on this rock is criminal.
我们应该做点什么
We should do something about it.
大黄蜂 我要知道他们为什么追杀人类
Bee, I need to know why they're killing humans.
咱们得找个砖家问问
I say we call in the expert.
下一位嘉宾是前美国情报人员
My next guest is a former American intelligence operative
他曾为我们爆出猛料
who has dared to speak out
关于我们国家宣称的军事同盟方是那些
regarding our alleged military alliance with what many describe
所谓的外星僱佣兵
as a group of extraterrestrial mercenaries.
他就是畅销书《代号：英雄》的作者
He is the author of the bestselling book, Code-Name Hero.
有请前探员 西摩·西蒙斯
Former special agent, Seymour Simmons.
比尔 我是你的粉丝 很高兴接受专访
Bill. Big fan. Great to be here.
西蒙斯探员 你想让我们相信
Now, Agent Simmons, you would have us believe
对我们来说最要紧的事情
that it is in our best interest
就是在这场外星人内战中选好阵营吗？
to formally take sides in this so-called alien civil war?
其中一派想把我们剁了做早餐吃
Well, the other side wanted to spank us for breakfast,
所以我们其实没什么选择余地
so I wouldn't exactly call it a toss-up.
那些霸天虎相当凶残
These Decepticons are lethal.
但民调显示世界上一半的人都认为更加安全
But polls show half the world would feel safer
假如汽车人离开地球的话
with the Autobots completely gone.
让他们滚出去！我们不需要他们！
Get them out of here! We don't need them here!
那为了安全 我只能抱着手榴弹睡觉了
I feel safer when I sleep with a hand grenade.
我这话未必对
Doesn't mean I'm always right.
探员先生 事实上我们得到的资料
Now, agent, here at The Factor we have obtained documents
表明你已被开除…
that show you were fired....
- 查斯 我在做访谈 - 抱歉 西蒙斯先生
- Chaz, I'm doing an interview. - Sorry, Mr. Simmons.
机构裁员而已
Downsized, Bill.
- 经费削减了 查斯 出去 - 这里是你的精神检验报告
- Budget cuts. Chaz, out. - Your psych evaluation reports
上面说你有“严重的妄想倾向”
"severe delusional tendencies."
你这是搞突袭啊
This is ambush journalism.
你想了解外星人联盟的真相吗？
You want the truth about the alien alliance?
买我的书！来买我的书 不然就没有了 各位！
Buy my book! Buy my book, before it's too late, people!
想跟我单挑是吧 比尔？
You want a piece of me, Bill?
想把我剥个精光？ 我恭候大驾！
You want to get naked? I'm ready!
采访结束了！
Interview is over!.
- 你 滚出我的房子！ - 你看起来就像个傻瓜
- You, out of my house. - You're sounding like a pinhead, agent
- 我给你个忠告吧  - 都结束了 懂不懂？
- And I've got a suggestion for you. - It's over. Understand?
- 赶快去看医生 - 达奇！
- Damage control. - Dutch!
你们明显惹恼了西蒙斯先生！
You have obviously upset Mr. Simmons!
23秒之内你们必须离开这里
You have 23 seconds to leave the property.
我已经叫警察了！
I have called the police!
你们这群乡巴佬真是自不量力！
You are peasant people throwing rocks at a giant!
接下来呢？有什么安排？
What's up next? What have we got?
签名售书 市中心 中午
Book signing, Midtown, noon.
然后我们送你去参加发现频道的真人秀节目
Then we pitch your reality show to the Discovery Channel.
还有那个维特维奇一直打电话找你
And I have this Witwicky who keeps calling me.
今天已5次电话了
Five times today.
那小子想干嘛？
Kid? What does he want?
我找你是因为霸天虎又回来了
I called you because the Decepticons are back.
我想知道原因 我需要你的帮助
I want to know why, and I need your help.
他们回来了？
They're back?
那么这下又有钱赚了
Well, that's good for business.
如果我告诉你我知道一个隐藏了50年的外星机密
What if I told you I know a 50-year-old alien secret
从未有人对你说过的
that nobody ever told you.
求你别再引诱我
Do not tempt my addiction.
我已经金盆洗手了 孩子
I have gone through withdrawal, kid.
- 达奇 这条线路安全吗？ - 不
- Dutch, is this line secure? - No.
别冒险 我现在有钱了 我图什么啊？
Don't take the risk. I'm rich, why should I?
不要再复出了 绝不能
Do not relapse. I won't.
别让让心中的恶魔卷土重来
Do not let the demons win.
可以了
Got it.
什么机密？
What kind of secret?
阿波罗 月亮 外星人 伪装…
Apollo. Moon. Aliens. Cover-up.
未来技术 暗杀 这类的机密
Future tech. Assassinations. That kind of stuff.
哦 阿波罗
Apollo.
达奇！
Dutch!
告诉威震天 哥重出江湖了
Tell Megatron, "Let's tango."
这颗星球多么壮丽而祥和啊
So majestic and peaceful, this planet.
哪像塞伯坦的末日景象
Unlike the final days of Cybertron.
我曾经想过
I've wondered what might have been
当初若是由您来指挥最后一战 而不是我
if you had fought the final battle, instead of me.
别追悔过去 年轻的战士
Never mourn the past, young warrior.
多亏了你 我们的种族才得以延续
Thanks to you, our race survives.
您曾是我们的领袖 御天敌
You were our leader, Sentinel.
您有权再次领导我们
It is your right to lead us again.
在这个我不熟悉的世界
In a world I do not know,
我不再是你的师长了 擎天柱 你才是我的老师
I am no longer your teacher, Optimus. You are mine.
这事得查个水落石出
You've got to break this case down.
宇航员倒楣也能传染给我们
What we have here is an astronaut epidemic.
失踪 死亡 死于交通事故 谋杀 送医不治 车祸
MIA. Dead. Died in a car accident. Killed. DOA. Car death.
像这群家伙不能驾驶
It's like these guys can't drive.
他们连飞船都能开上天 居然开不好车
They can fly into outer space, but they can't drive a car.
这是你要的情报 维特维奇
Procured your information, Witwicky.
谢谢你 布鲁斯
Thank you, Bruce.
慢着
Now,
让我看一眼 就这一次
let me see one right now. One time.
- 要快 - 没问题
- Quick. - Very.
探月轨道飞行器
Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter.
国航局于2009年发射
It says NASA launched it in 2009.
看 庭审记录显示老王可能篡改了代码
See, forensics show Wang may have messed with the code,
导致无法测绘月球远端
preventing it from mapping the far side of the moon,
也就是月球背面
which is also the dark side.
太酷了
Fucking awesome.
他们搞渗透 搞恐吓
They infiltrate us, intimidate us,
逼迫人类给他们干肮脏勾当
coerce us to do their dirty work.
一旦事成后
And once they're done,
就在脑袋上来两枪
a double-tap to the cerebellum.
也就是说有人类在为霸天虎做事
So humans are working for the Decepticons.
我觉得霸天虎不是
I don't think this is about the Decepticons
在月球上找什么东西
looking for something on the moon.
我觉得他们是想要隐藏什么
I think it's about something they wanted to hide.
跟老爸玩玩
Come to Daddy.
来吧 过两招
Come on, throw down.
你小时候是不是脑袋让驴踢了？
Did you eat a lot of paint chips when you were a kid?
真胡闹！
He's a freak.
- 喜欢吗？ - 回来！
- Like it?    - Get back!
我会教你！
I'm ticklish!
先生！我在召开一个外星人情报高端分析会议
Sir! We are having a pretty high-level alien intel confab here
我想你没有资格参加 跟班小弟
that I don't think you're cleared for, errand boy.
对 你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
- 这机器人真给力  - 你该走了 布鲁斯
- It's a bitching robot. - I think it's time to go, Bruce.
- 多谢你让我开了眼界… - 走吧 布鲁斯
- Thank you so much for this. And... - Got to go, Bruce.
我忙得浑身冒烟
I'm smoking over here.
关于那些失踪的苏联宇航员
Downloading missing Russian cosmonauts.
前苏联曾经取消了一次载人登月计划
Turns out the Soviets canceled a manned mission to the moon.
那是1972年的事
The moon, in 1972.
后来其中两个宇航员潜逃到了美国
And two of their cosmonauts went into hiding in America.
我刚刚发现了他们
And I just found them alive.
你真是个天才 聪明鬼
You're a genius, Brains.
看你干的好事 大黄蜂
That was smooth, Bumblebee.
就差那么一点
Missed it by that much.
嗨
Hi.
谁能告诉我这是怎么回事？
Would somebody care to tell me what the hell's going on?
- 你是谁？ - 你是谁？
- Who are you? - Who are you?
居然问我？那个谁？达奇！搜她的身！
Who am I? Who is that? Dutch! Frisk her!
遵命
Certainly.
等等 达奇
No. Dutch.
别碰我
Don't touch me.
- 我没打算碰  - 山姆？
- I'm not gonna touch her. - Sam?
宝贝
Angel.
我在工作 很抱歉
I was working. I'm sorry about this.
- 太好了 又要无家可归了 - 她住在这里？
- Great. We're homeless. - She lives here?
你真该搜她身
You had your chance to frisk her.
- 我有女友的 - 是吗？那她叫什么？
- I have a girlfriend. - Really? What's her name?
印度
India.
我们要去参加迪伦的晚会 忘了吗？
We're supposed to be at Dylan's party, remember?
我没忘 但这些人是我的朋友
I do remember, but these are my friends.
他们需要我 我现在走不开
They need me. I have to be here right now.
那又怎样 汽车人和军方不能自己解决问题吗？
So, what, the Autobots and the military, they can't handle this on their own?
知道我为什么喜欢你的战争故事吗？
You know what I liked about your war stories, Sam?
因为它们仅仅是故事而已 都过去了
It's that they were stories, they were in the past.
听着 我知道你又想起你牺牲的哥哥
Look, I know you're thinking about your brother, okay?
你在想你的家人
And you're thinking about your family.
但现在情况不同
And it's not that situation.
- 不同？ - 不同
- No?            - No.
有什么不同？为何怎么不同？
Why not? Why isn't it, Sam?
你觉得我们拿奖章好还是看到他活着好？
You think we'd rather have his medals, or we'd rather have him?
你说得对 我明白了
I hear you. I get it.
你要带我的幸运兔去哪？ 站住！
Where are you taking my bunny? Stop!
求你先别走
Just stop for a second.
我昨晚彻夜未眠
You think I could sleep last night?
总算想明白了 山姆就是喜欢冒险
And then it hit me. No, Sam wants to be in danger.
- 不然他都不知道自己是谁了 - 我只想让你看得起我
- He doesn't know who he is without it. - I just want to matter.
我看得起你
You matter to me.
我知道你很担心 你非常担心我
I know you're worried. I know you're worried.
但我向你保证 我会照顾好自己
But I promise you, I can handle this.
你能保证吗？
Can you? You can promise it?
我保证
I promise.
山姆 我不想失去你 我知道结果会怎样
Sam, I don't want to lose you, and I know where this leads.
我还没心理准备
I'm not ready for this.
你跟我一起去吗？
Are you coming with me?
抱歉
I can't.
好吧
Okay.
嘿
Hey.
你的兔脚
Here's your foot.
真正的勇士总是独来独往
The warrior's path is a solitary one.
天啊 她怎么买得起那种车？
How the hell did she afford that car?
- 老板送的 - 有钱的混蛋！
- Her boss. - Rich bastards!
以前我也讨厌他们 现在嘛…
I used to hate them. Now, it's...
我们去黑帮追查两个前苏联宇航员
Going to a gig on the hunt for two Russian cosmonauts.
什么也比不上开迈巴赫拉风 是吧？
Nothing like driving in a Maybach.
德国人造的车没得说
Germans know how to make cars, let me tell you.
我的小达奇 原国家安全局的网络讯息高手
My Dutchman, former NSA cybersleuth extraordinaire,
他查到他们就在这里
tracked them down here.
为什么这些宇航员要躲藏起来？为什么？
So, these cosmonauts went into hiding. Why?
宾果 完全吻合
Bingo. I got a match.
达奇 你真是头德国牧羊犬
You're a German Shepherd, Dutch.
俄国人有个毛病 就是不爱多说话
The thing about Russians is, they never like to talk.
我得用点“国际通用语”
It's gonna take a little of the "international language."
（等会见）
那意思是“再见”
That means "good-bye."
来点带劲的
没问题
- 你真迷人 - 你嘴真甜
别紧张
Stay loose.
达奇 给我来句狠话
Dutch, give me something tough.
巴雷什尼科夫
Baryshnikov.
我们会说英语
We do speak English.
达奇 你真丢人
Dutch, you suck.
这是古斯拉夫语
It's a Cyrillic alphabet.
就像你在计算机上从不去按的那些生僻按键！
It's like all the buttons you never push on a calculator!
我才不丢人呢
I don't suck.
我是西摩·西蒙斯特工 来自第八区 过去的第七区
Agent Seymour Simmons, Sector Eight, formerly Seven.
我们知道你们是谁 前苏联宇航员
We know who you are, cosmonautchiks.
那又怎样？
So what?
你们本来要执行一次登陆月球背面的任务
You were supposed to travel to the dark side of the moon,
但最终任务取消了
then it all got shut down.
我们想知道为什么？
The question is, why?
这三个人脑子有毛病吗？
谁放他们进来的？
“我的孩子能在这里抽烟吗？”
"Can my child smoke in here?"
这些人我都不认识
他们怎么进来的啊
- 我怎么知道 - 叫保安来 快快！ 现在就叫
愣着干嘛！
好 没问题 好
Okay, all right. Okay.
来啊 开枪啊
Go ahead, shoot me.
你来这里想干什么？
我可以为国捐躯 你行吗？
I'm willing to die for my country. Are you?
你给我闭嘴 老实滚出去
真的吗？
Really?
你真美 有人说过你很美吗？
You are beautiful. Has anyone ever told you you're beautiful?
她是位美丽的女人
She's a beautiful woman.
达奇！给我乖一点
Dutch! Back in the cage.
达奇！住手 达奇 住手！
Dutch! Hold, Dutch, hold!
管好你的人 别让他乱来！
Control your boy, please. Control your boy.
达奇 住手！
Dutch, stop!
真抱歉 刚才是过去的我
I'm so sorry. That is the old me.
好了 大家都冷静下来！
Okay, let's everybody just calm down!
让我们都把枪放下 放轻松
Let's lower the heat, lower the guns. Let's relax.
二战已经结束了
World War II is over.
你们即将看到前苏联最重要的机密之一
You are about to see one of the biggest Soviet secrets.
美国第一个把人类送上了月球
America first to send man to the moon.
但苏联却是抢先把照相机送了上去
But USSR first to send camera.
1959年 我们的月球3号
In 1959, our Luna 3
拍摄了月球背面的照片
take picture of the dark, the shadow side.
空无一物
Sees nothing.
但到了1963年 月球4号发现了…
But in 1963, Luna 4 sees...
- 奇怪的石堆 - 对
- Strange rocks. - Yeah.
就在飞船周围 有好几百块
Around the ship. Hundreds of them.
给他们看照片
Yeah, show picture.
还有些拖拽的痕迹
With some drag marks.
我见过这个 这些不是石头 是能量柱
I've seen these. These aren't rocks, these are pillars.
用来建造太空桥的能量柱
Alien pillars for a space bridge.
我们知道这些 是因为汽车人手里有五根
We know about them because the Autobots have five of these.
霸天虎一定是在阿波罗11号抵达之前就突袭过飞船
The Decepticons must have raided the ship before Apollo 11 ever got there,
拿走了能量柱 并将之藏了起来
took the pillars, and hid them.
但这不合逻辑
It doesn't make sense.
霸天虎找到了飞船 也拿走了全部能量柱
The Decepticons have the ship. They have all those pillars.
那为什么偏偏留下了御天敌呢？
Why would they leave Sentinel
他可是唯一会使用能量柱的
when he's the only one who can use them?
除非…
Unless...
他就是霸天虎仍然觊觎的目标
He's the one thing they still need.
我们得赶紧去找御天敌
We've got to meet up with Sentinel,
守在他身旁 保卫他的安全
rendezvous with him and keep him safe.
梅琳 我刚刚找到御天敌 擎天柱10分钟后就到
Mearing, I just picked up Sentinel. Optimus is 10 minutes behind.
我们正在返回NEST
We're coming to NEST now.
维特维奇先生 我记得提醒过你
Mr. Witwicky, I thought I made it clear to you
不要再打这个电话了
that I did not want you calling this phone.
听着 整件事都是个陷阱
Listen, the whole thing has been a setup since the beginning.
霸天虎希望擎天柱找到御天敌
The Decepticons wanted Optimus to find Sentinel
因为只有擎天柱才能复活他
because only Optimus could revive him.
但太空桥在我们手中
But we have the space bridge.
梅琳 你手中只有5个能量柱
Mearing, you have five pillars.
我刚刚得知霸天虎有几百个
I just learned that they have hundreds.
你是在被他们牵着鼻子走
You're doing exactly what they wanted you to do.
我要跟你说的是
What do you need me to say to you?
霸天虎很快就会来找御天敌
The Decepticons are coming for Sentinel Prime!
我们马上出发去NEST
We're going to NEST.
能量警报！
We have an Energon alert.
在华盛顿州际公路上发现能量讯号…
Energon readings detected on the D. C. Parkway.
正在追踪三辆黑色越野车
Currently tracking three black Suburbans.
大黄蜂 你掩护御天敌离开这里
Bee, you got to get Sentinel out of here! You got to guard him!
噢 天啊 我要被炒鱿鱼了
Oh, mein Gott! I'm fired!
当心！ 当心！ 当心！
Watch out! Watch out! Watch out!
抓住你了
Got you!
射击！射击！打死他 大黄蜂！
Shoot him! Shoot him! Shoot him, Bee!
大黄蜂 再开快点！再快 快！
Bee, you've got to move faster! Faster, Bee! Go!
大黄蜂！
Bee!
好了 回NEST去！
All right, back to NEST!
恐龙 我来对付他！
Dino, I got him!
铁皮！
Ironhide!
有什么问题吗？
Is there a problem?
哇哦 搞得跟西部片对决一样
A little Mexican standoff we got here.
放下武器
Weapons down.
我们会让你们体面地离开
And we'll let you escape with your dignity.
丢掉武器
Drop them.
很好
That's good.
铁皮 当心！
Ironhide, watch out!
铁皮 接枪！
Ironhide, catch!
当心背后
Behind you!
霸天虎小混混
Decepticon punk!
管教完毕
Class dismissed.
- 都进去！走吧！ - 快点！动作快！
- Get inside! Let's go! - Move! Keep moving!
- 伦诺克斯！ - 快 快 快！
- Lennox!        - Go, go, go!
到处都是霸天虎
We got Decepticons everywhere.
我已经派出全部人马去搜捕他们了 铁皮！
I've got my whole team deployed looking for them. Ironhide!
保护御天敌！带他到里面去！
Protect Sentinel! Get him locked up inside!
包在我身上
Consider it done!
你要保卫好他 他是整件事的关键
Hey, you've got to guard him, 'cause he's the key to the whole thing.
说得没错 你们必须意识到 汽车人兄弟们
Indeed, I am. What you must realize, my Autobot brothers,
我们当年根本赢不了那场战争
is we were never going to win the war.
为了保存住我们的母星
For the sake of our planet's survival,
我不得不和威震天做了笔交易
a deal had to be made with Megatron.
- 退后！ - 你这是干什么？
- Get back! - What have you done?
我马上就让你解脱
I hereby discharge you from duty.
- 大黄蜂！ - 退后！
- Bee!      - Get back!
NEST全部人马撤回基地！快点！
Rally all NEST forces back to the base! Come on!
不…
No...
叫个医疗兵来！
Get a medic down here!
我们人手不足！不要和御天敌交战！
We don't have enough men! Do not engage Sentinel!
我们走后门
Just go to the back gate.
卧倒！
Tak e cover!
注意左边！注意左边！
Watch left! Watch left!
快点！跟我来！
Let's go! Follow me!
- 局长 别去那儿！ - 退后！
- Director, don't go there! - Stand down!
嘿 御天敌！
Hey, Sentinel!
- 局长！ - 出什么事了？
- Director! - What is going on?
你这是在干什么？
What do you think you are doing?
我是首领！
I am a Prime!
不会听命于你
I do not take orders from you.
梅琳局长 拜托
Director Mearing, come on.
我们打不过他 走吧 我们必须离开
We can't fight him. Let's go. We have to go.
现在把我的东西还给我！
Now return what belongs to me!
哦 我的天啊！
Oh, my God!
- 你们还好吗？ - 大家都出去了？
- You guys okay? - Is everybody out?
各位 保持镇静 你们会没事的
Everybody, stay calm. You're gonna be fine.
你看看 擎天柱！这都是你的错！
Yeah, take a look, Optimus! This is all on you!
御天敌破坏了仓库！抢走了能量柱
Sentinel hit the vault! Took the pillars.
快 我们走 通知101空降师！
Come on, let's go. All right, notify the 101St Airborne!
我们得抓住那个家伙！
We need to hunt this thing down!
卡莉！
Carly!
这么一小堆篝火还挺热的
Hot from our little campfire.
夹心巧克力饼 多美妙啊
S'mores. Isn't that great?
简直是在世外桃源
We're really living off the land.
妈 爸 你们见到卡莉回家了吗？
Mom, Dad, have you guys seen Carly come home yet?
我说 你就不会敲门吗？这是我们的卧室
Excuse me. Can you knock, please? This is our bedroom.
她难道会不回家吗？
Why wouldn't she be at home?
我们吵架了或许分手了
We had a fight and we might have broken up,
也可能只是暂时分开 我不太清楚
or be on a break. I don't really know.
- 什么？不  - 我不想谈这事
- What? No. - Look, I can't talk about it right now.
妈 我不想谈细节 我必须找到她
I can't go into details, Mom. I have to find her.
坐下 我们开个家庭会议！家庭会议！
Sit down. We're having a family meeting. Family meeting!
也许你不知道
You may not know this,
其实你爸和我也不是一直这么恩爱
but your father and I were not always this perfectly happy.
结婚这些年来有一段时期
You know, there was a time in our marriage
我认为没法再继续下去了
when I thought this was not gonna work out.
- 能别说这个吗？ - 她伤害了他
- Can we please not? - She's damaging him.
你和一个世界级美人儿分手…
You break up with one world-class hottie...
不 别说了 停下 好吗？她甩了我
No. Stop. Stop, okay? She dumped me,
我再去找个更好的 不就行了吗 我还更幸福呢
I moved on to something better. That's it. I'm a happier person.
这是第二个漂亮姑娘了 你又让她跑了
The second beautiful girl, and you lose her.
为何你不帮我一把呢？
Why don't you help me?
- 他们只是发生争执 - 只是吵架
- They had an argument. - One fight.
你很难再找到第三个了 我是说 除非你那个很大…
You're not gonna get a third one, I mean, unless you have like a big...
我晕 老妈！
What the... Ma!
你大概都不知道自己在干什么
Maybe you just don't know what you're doing.
- 我不想再说了 - 你需要这本书
- I don't want to talk about this anymore. - You need the book.
- 跟他说说这本书 - 男人永远是错的 慢慢习惯吧
- Tell him about the book. - You're always wrong. Get used to it.
好吧 你应该读一读 《女人至上》
Okay. You've gotta read this. She Comes First.
- 这里头有些很有用的知识 - 不 不
- There's some killer shit in here. - No. No.
- 就这样 来吧 - 不！不！
- That's it, I'm going. - No! No!
坐下 坐下！帮帮我！
Sit down, sit down! Back me up!
- 老婆开心 生活舒心 - 没错
- Happy wife, happy life. - Heck yeah.
老婆不满 余生冰冷如石一般悲惨…
Unhappy wife, stone-cold misery for the rest of your...
- 闭嘴 - 是实话
- Stop. - It's true.
我想说的是 你爱这女孩吗？
All I'm saying is, do you love this girl?
- 这辈子就认她了 - 那就去把她追回来
- She's the one. - Then you gotta go get her.
告诉你 你爸和我吵架的时候
I mean, your dad and I, when we had troubles,
他会上天入地去找我
he moved heaven and earth to find me.
告诉他你怎么说的 说嘛
Say what you said. Say it.
“我会陪你直到地老天荒”
"I will follow you to the end of time."
听起来很傻吧？
Does that suck or what?
- 就像狗屎科幻电影一样 - 不 很浪漫啊
- It's like a bad sci-fi film. - No. It is so sweet.
你们得离开这个城市 走得越远越好
I want you to get out of the city. You get as far away from here as you can.
明白吗？
You understand?
我爱你们
I love you.
主人！多么完美的计划！
My master! Such a brilliant scheme!
原来御天敌离开塞伯坦时 就已经是叛徒了？
So when Sentinel left Cybertron, it was to defect?
他本该和我在地球会合
He was meant to rendezvous with me here on Earth
谁知命运使我们擦肩而过
before fate waylaid us both.
复活他的唯一途径
The only way to revive him,
就是擎天柱和他的领导模块
we needed Prime and his Matrix.
高明的策略
Excellent strategy.
我的 我的！
Mine, mine!
他现在是您的伙伴了 主人？
So he is now your partner, master?
他是我最伟大的战利品
He is my greatest triumph.
我对您五体投地
So impressive.
开始传输
Commencing transport.
住手！不！不 御天敌！
Stop! No! No, Sentinel!
原谅我
Forgive me.
我们来了
Here we are.
和我们战斗吧
Fight us now.
小心！快走！快走！
Watch out! Move it! Move it!
汽车人 撤退！
Autobots, retreat!
为什么 御天敌 为什么？
Why, Sentinel, why?
为了塞伯坦！为了我们的家园！
For Cybertron! For our home!
战争的破坏我们可以修复！
What war destroyed, we can rebuild!
但必须和霸天虎合作
But only if we join with the Decepticons.
不 还有别的方法
No, it's not the only way.
这里才是我们的家！
This is our home!
我们必须保护人类！
We must defend the humans!
你误入歧途了 擎天柱
So lost you are, Optimus.
在塞伯坦 我们被敬若神明
On Cybertron, we were gods.
这里 地球人叫我们机器
And here, they call us machines.
让人类成为我们的奴仆 否则就灭亡
Let the humans serve us, or perish.
我没杀你算你走运 将来你会明白的
You're lucky I didn't kill you. In time you'll see.
这还不算完
It's not over.
如果我是他 我一秒钟都不会让你离开我的视线
Now, if I were him, I wouldn't let you out of my sight for one second.
有意思 来这的路上我一直琢磨
It's funny. I was just thinking on the way over here,
我真的需要迪伦给点建议 而他就在这里
I could really use some advice from Dylan, and there he is.
- 能跟你谈谈吗 卡莉？ - 欢迎 请坐
- Can I speak to you, Carly? - Welcome. Please, sit down.
喝杯酒吧
Have a drink.
老实说 我不想喝酒 也不在乎车子或工作
You know what, I don't need a drink. Or a car, or a job.
我就想和我女友单独谈谈
I just need to speak to my girlfriend alone.
你不会介意吧 电灯泡先生？
Is that okay with you, Mr. Inappropriate?
不好意思
Excuse me.
- 出什么事了？ - 到外面再说
- What's going on? - I'll tell you outside.
我认为我能帮你 山姆
I really think I can help you, Sam.
我曾和父亲探讨如何做出抉择
I remember a talk I had with my dad once about tough choices.
可惜现在不是时候 咱们回头再聊
Yeah, now's not the time. We'll set something up, though.
当然那是很久以前了 那时我父亲的公司还在…
Of course, it was way back, when my dad's firm was in charge
为国家航空航天局做经费预算和财务报表
of budget review and accounting for NASA.
他教给我的是…
You see, the thing that he taught me was,
如果这战争与你无关
when it's not your war,
那就最好站在能赢的那方
you join the side that's going to win.
走
Move.
太直接了？我的老毛病？
Too direct? Or is it just me?
一点也不
Certainly not you, sir.
你是我的了！
You're mine!
不！
No!
- 来人啊！ - 山姆 我无法出来！
- Get help! - Sam, I can't get out!
- 谁来救救她！ - 晚安！
- Someone get help! - Good night!
晚安 迪伦先生
Good night, Mr. Dylan.
山姆 救我出去！
Get me out of here!
救命！救救她！
Help! Get help!
- 他还年轻 还要深造 晚安 - 救我出去！
- He's young. He will learn. Good night. - Get me out!
今晚很愉快
It was a fun night.
你真的以为自己是第一个
You really think you're the first man
涉足外星人事务的人吗？
ever asked to join the noble alien cause?
你到底是谁？
Who are you?
你知道为什么1972年之后我们再也没有登月吗？
Do you know why we've not been back to the moon since 1972?
因为这两位
Because these two,
他们来找我父亲 要求他伪造一些账目
they came to my dad and they told him to do some creative accounting.
拼命拔高预算而无法再次登月
Make it way too expensive to ever go back.
因此他和其它人终止了美苏两国的太空计划
So, he and the others shut down the American and Russian space programs.
自此这二位便成为了我们的客户
And they've been our clients ever since.
你帮他们杀人？
You think they'd give you a choice?
你以为我有得选择吗？
再说 我个人也没有参与
Besides, it's not like I personally participated.
我只是个联络人 只负责传话
I am a liaison. I liaise.
该是坏人出场的时候了 山姆
It's hostile takeover time, Sam.
山姆！
Sam!
- 山姆！ - 放她走！
- Sam! - Let her go!
山姆！
Sam!
我监视你很多年了 山姆
I've had my eye on you for years, Sam.
我一直无法在汽车人身边安插间谍
You're the one spy I've never been able to provide
而某人却可以轻易做到
as someone close to the Autobots.
山姆 别照他说的做！
Sam! Don't do what he wants!
他会的
Yes, he will.
他们都会
They all do.
他们会杀了她 你懂吗？
They will slaughter her, you understand me?
只要一眨眼的功夫 他们就会杀了她 然后杀了我
In the time it takes you to blink, they'll do it to her and they'll do it to me.
所以 你至少该尊重下
So you show a little respect
那个给你推荐工作的人！
when someone offers you a job!
手腕
Wrist.
你要去找擎天柱
You are to track down Optimus Prime,
因为在人类中他最信任你
because you're the one human he trusts,
你要问他一个问题
and you will ask one question.
他打算如何反击？
How does he intend to fight back?
什么策略 什么战术 全都给我套出来！
Strategies, tactics, everything!
咬得够狠吧 对不对？这可是高科技
Has a nasty little bite, doesn't it? It's very high-tech.
它能让我们看你所看 听你所听
It lets us see what you see, hear what you hear
还能介入你的神经系统
and it taps your nervous system.
所以你不要妄想警告其他人…
So, if you so much as try and signal...
我要告诉你 山姆
I don't know what to tell you, Sam.
人际关系决定命运 我站在这儿是因为我父亲
Relationships have consequences. I am here because of my father.
她待在这儿是因为你
She is here because of you.
住手 住手 住手 住手！
Stop, stop! Stop! Stop!
声波 收敛点行吗？
Soundwave, would you please?
山姆 你乖乖办事
Sam, do your job.
她会没事的 我向你保证
She'll be safe. I give you my word.
我会杀了你 我也向你保证
I'll kill you. You have my word.
指挥中心已发布一级战备状态
Combatant Commands are now at DEFCON 1.
世界各地潜伏着大约两百个霸天虎
Approximately 200 Decepticons are now in hiding.
检测到超能量的存在
Energon detectors have been triggered
甚至远至南美和中国
as far away as South America and China.
联合国刚刚收到一份加密音频文件
The U. N. Just received an encrypted audio file.
是来自汽车人的领袖
They say it's from the leader of the Autobots.
地球的保卫者们
Defenders of Earth.
我们来到这里寻求自然资源
We have come for your natural resources
以重建我们满目疮痍的母星
to rebuild our damaged planet.
我们的所有要求得到满足后
When we have transported all we need,
就会和平地离开地球
we will leave your world in peace.
为了保证这份和平
For such peace to exist,
你们必须立即驱逐已收留的汽车人叛逆
you must immediately exile the Autobot rebels you have harbored.
没有谈判的余地
Nonnegotiable.
立即驱逐那些叛逆
Renounce the rebels.
我们等候你们的答覆
We await your reply.
我们会跟进你的情报
We'll debrief you in transit.
我不知道能帮什么忙
Yeah, I really don't see how I can be of any help.
再说你们也挺忙的
I mean, you guys seem pretty busy.
我们可以下次再谈
We could just do this another time, I think.
看来我过去真是低估了你了
I have underestimated you at every turn.
啊… 什么？
What?
你提醒过我们 他们在利用人类
You warned us that they were using humans.
也说过御天敌是全局的关键
And you knew that Sentinel was the key.
局长！
Director!
我算啥啊？你们才是专家 我只是个会泄露机密的家伙
Who am I? Hey, you're the expert. I'm just a walking security risk.
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
没事
Yes.
- 不对 你出了很多汗 - 我没事 我没事
- No, you're not. You're sweating. - I'm fine. I'm fine.
我出汗是因为我紧张
I'm sweating because I'm nervous.
我紧张是因为你把这些讯息告诉给我
I'm nervous because you got me in here with this information.
好吧 我用推特上瘾了 我博客上什么都写
Okay, I'm a Twitter junkie. I blog everything.
- 我不能保守秘密来保命 - 你不敢的
- I can't keep a secret to save my life. - You wouldn't dare.
是真的 我不骗你
That's the truth. I'm telling you.
局长 15号线有五角大楼的电话
Director, the Pentagon's calling in 15.
- 你在干什么？ - 没什么 你在干什么？
- What are you doing? - Nothing. What are you doing?
离我远点
Get away from me.
今天在国会发生的事件具有重大意义
It's been a remarkable series of events today at the Capitol.
就在不久之前 国会通过法案
Just moments ago, legislation was passed
决定将汽车人驱逐出
to exile the Autobots
美国领土
from American shores.
美军与他们的盟友关系正式宣告结束
The U. S. Military alliance with them is officially over.
正如议会中多数党领袖…
In the words of the House Majority Leader,
就本次决议回答了提问
the sponsor of today's resolution,
- “我们的良心不允许我们…” - 好的
- "We cannot in good conscience.... " - Okay.
什么？他们不能这么做
What? They can't do this.
你得告诉他们 他们不能这样做
You gotta tell them. They can't do that.
好的 政府已经下令 行动吧
Okay. It's official. It's a go, people.
汽车人是我们的盟友 我们曾并肩作战 生死与共
These are our allies. The Autobots fought for us. They fought with us.
结果怎么样呢？
And where are we now?
兵临城下
Facing an enemy invasion
而且敌方兵力无法估量
with an enemy that has the means to deploy countless more.
如果你还知道些什么
If there is any more you know,
任何关于敌人意图的讯息
anything at all about the enemy's intentions,
现在该告诉我了
now is the time to tell.
汽车人没办法离开地球
Autobots have no way of leaving this planet.
你说错了
And that is where you're wrong.
飞船名叫苍耳号
Its name is the Xanthium.
就是它运来了第二批汽车人
It brought the second wave of Autobots
此后一直由国家航空航天局保管和研究
and it's been under NASA 's care and study ever since.
我们将它和一艘退役航天飞机捆绑
We linked it with a decommissioned shuttle
使其在汽车人离开之前都处于军方控制之下
to maintain military control until they're gone.
那个脆弱的螺栓将承受到一万磅的扭力 不是19！
Gonna be 10,000 pounds of torque on that itsy-bitsy bolt, not 19!
你们是在拿我同伴的生命冒险！鄙视你们！
You're gonna risk the lives of all me mates! I'll ball you!
那是雷霆拯救队 他们负责维护苍耳号
These guys are the Wreck ers. They take care of the Xanthium.
我们一般不让他们离开基地 因为他们都不是好鸟
We don't let them off the base much, 'cause they're assholes.
你要用力拉 你个废物！
You gotta pull that, ya nancy swanker!
扭力太强了会杀了他的！
It's time to kill him!
我只是帮忙而已 做我本职工作
I'm just trying to help, you know. Just doing my job.
冷静点 离他远点 这是人类
Just calm down. Leave him alone. This is a human being.
- 艾普斯！ - 你简直不可理喻！
- Epps! - You are ridiculous!
- 是你吗？ - 嗨 伙计！
- Is that you? - What up, man?
你怎么在这里？
What are you doing here?
我从空军退役了
I retired from the Air Force.
放开我的手行吗？
Can you let my hand go?
你这是怎么了？
What the hell was that?
退役后我来到这儿做顾问和协调工作
Now I just consult to run interference for them.
你是在帮倒忙！
Well, you're not helping!
不用打仗也不用被外星人追杀 我得到了理想的工作
No more combat and aliens shooting at my ass. I got a dream job.
是时候占领这个星球了
Time to get off this planet.
他们要把汽车人赶走 你能相信这样的事吗？
Kicking the Autobots out. Can you believe this is happening?
你知道他们要飞往哪里吗？
Where do you think it's taking them?
总之是地球之外的地方
Any planet but here.
我想和这里的头儿谈谈
I wanna talk to whoever's in charge here!
我还以为是谁呢
Well, well, well.
是夏洛特·梅琳
Charlotte Mearing.
西蒙斯探员 前探员西蒙斯
Agent Simmons. Former Agent Simmons.
看来你没死在华盛顿
So I see you survived Washington.
华盛顿 埃及 失恋 我挺过来了 我还会活下去的
Washington, Egypt, heartbreak. I survive. I will survive.
他们正在动员所有的情报人员
They're bringing everybody in, kid.
情报人员正在汇集所有的情报
Putting all the intel on the table.
如果你以为驱逐9个汽车人就能解决问题的话…
And if you think deporting nine Autobots is gonna solve a damn thing...
这事我做不了主
It's out of my hands.
看来你高升了？
Moving up in the world?
你的臀部真美
Your booty looks excellent.
你要是敢跟别人说起
If you ever say a word to anyone
在匡提科那晚发生的事
about what happened that night in Quantico,
我就把你的心掏出来
I'll cut your heart out.
你早就掏走了
You already did.
山姆 听我说 别让他们驱逐我们
Sammy, listen to me. Don't let them exile us.
- 别抛弃我们 山姆 - 这是霸天虎的圈套
- Don't let them take us, Sam. - It's a Decepticon trap.
检查氮气量 我们准备发射
Check the nitrogen levels. We're booking out of here.
擎天柱？
Optimus?
你们的领导人说得对 这都是我的错
What your leaders say is true. This was all my fault.
我告诉他们谁值得信赖 实在是大错特错
I told them whom to trust. I was so wrong.
那不怪你 只是这举动更像人类而已
That doesn't make it your fault. It just makes you human for a change.
记住
Remember this.
你们可以对我们失去信心
You may lose your faith in us,
但绝不要对自己失去信心
but never in yourselves.
我想知道你打算如何反击
I need to know how you're gonna fight back.
我知道你一定有策略 我知道你们会回来
I know this is strategy, I know you're coming back
会带援军什么的回来 我知道你们有计划
with reinforcements, something. I know there's a plan.
你可以跟我说 其他人不会知道的
You can tell me. No other human will ever know.
没有计划
There is no plan.
我们要是照他们说的做 到时该如何面对自己呢？
If we just do what they want, how are we gonna live with ourselves?
你是我的朋友 山姆
You are my friend, Sam.
永远都是
You always will be.
但你们的领导人已经做出了决定
But your leaders have spoken.
从现在起
From here,
你们只能孤军奋战了
the fight will be your own.
长话短说
Make it short.
我们要上船了
We're loading up.
好了 动作快点！天亮就发射
All right, hustle up! We're launching at dawn.
我们会尽自己所能 让地球得到保护
We're gonna do whatever we can. Make it like it was.
你永远是我的朋友 山姆
You will always be my friend, Sam.
我该走了
I gotta be going on.
多年以后 若子孙们问起
Years from now, they're gonna ask us,
当年它们占领地球的时候你们在哪里？
"Where were you when they took over the planet?"
我们只能说
We're gonna say,
我们只是在袖手旁观
"We just stood by and watched."
早上6:30
你真的应当把这看成是一种合作关系
You should really look at this as a partnership.
你应当站在进步的一方
You have to stand on the side of progress
如果你想书写历史的话
if you wanna be a part of history.
七 六 五
Seven, six, five,
四 三 二
four, three, two,
一 零
one, zero.
发射成功 全速推进
Go ahead and throttle up.
你想要答案 你已经拿到了
You wanted an answer. You got one.
我想要的都能到手 山姆
I always get what I want, Sam.
我们只是想确认一下
We just needed to be sure.
确认什么？
Sure of what?
他们乖乖上路了
That they would go without a fight.
- 再说一遍 - 探测到不明目标
- Say again. - Tracking an incoming object.
我们现在都是在为霸天虎卖命
We all work for the Decepticons now.
芝加哥市 伊利诺伊州
我需要你帮忙追踪一个电话 那人在这个手机上
I need your help to track a phone call. There's a man on this phone.
他是霸天虎的人类代表 并且抓走了卡莉作人质
He's the head of their human operations and he has Carly hostage.
你给我坐好了 别动
I want you to sit down. Don't move.
跟我来
Follow me.
他马上就开过来
I'm watching him drive up right now.
电话是在路上打出的
The call was placed en route.
我现在要侵入手机摄像头
I'm hacking into the phone's camera now.
看 这是摄像头的实时画面
There, that's it. That's a live stream from the camera.
这地方我来确定手机通讯基站位置
Someplace... Hold on. I can triangulate this.
确认 是芝加哥的基站 那里 找到了
Okay, it's Chicago cell sites. There, I've got it.
特朗普大厦 芝加哥 矮的那栋
Trump Tower, Chicago. Lower penthouse.
准备好了
We're on.
- 我要去那里 - 你确定吗？
- I'm going. - You sure?
谢谢你帮了我 我十五个小时之内要赶到
She's done nothing but try to help me, and I can be there in 15 hours.
不能让你一个人去
You're not going alone.
在那里还有我的NEST老战友
I still got my NEST friends out there.
我会召集起他们 找到你的女友
I'll round them up, we'll find your girlfriend,
然后逮住那家伙
we're gonna bring this guy in.
你为什么要帮我？
Why are you helping me?
因为那个混账也害死了我的朋友
'Cause that asshole killed my friends, too.
他们说想要地球的资源
They said they were here for our resources,
重建他们的星球
to rebuild their planet.
没错 但事实上只需要一种资源
Yes, but really one resource in particular.
我们星球上独一无二的资源
One unique to our planet.
我们？
Us?
你很聪明
You're very smart.
没有劳动力他们无法重建家园
You see, they can't rebuild without a slave labor force.
有哪个星球能提供60亿工人呢？
How many rocks up there in the universe offer six billion workers?
你什么意思？我们无法运送这么多人
What are you talking about? We can't transport people.
用不着把人带走 他们会把星球运到这里来
They're not shipping people. They're shipping their planet here.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
御天敌在这里干什么？
What's Sentinel doing here?
看吧 他们将数百能量柱放置在全球各地
Watch. They're spreading hundreds of pillars around the globe right now.
几个小时后 等它们被发射到轨道上启动后
In just a few hours, they're gonna launch them into orbit
就会将塞伯坦传送到我们的世界
and bring Cybertron into our atmosphere.
红色的那根是主控柱
The red one there controls the rest.
一旦激活 传输就将全面启动
He triggers that, it starts the whole thing.
滚开 小肉虫 你的任务已经结束了
Be gone, insect operative. Your work is done.
遵命 阁下 他真是个混蛋
Your Excellency. He's such a dick.
- 你希望悲剧发生吗？ - 我只希望能活着 多活40年而已
- You want this to happen? - I want to survive. I want 40 more years.
你以为我想这样啊？这都是客户要求
You think I asked for this? I inherited a client.
是啊 等塞伯坦来了 人类全成了奴隶
Yeah, and when Cybertron's here and we're all their slaves,
估计到时也需要个工头吧
I guess they'll still need a human leader.
少咒我 想活命就听我的
Don't jinx me. You want to survive, you listen to me.
该让地球上的奴隶们认识他们的新主子了
It is time for the slaves of Earth to recognize their masters.
封锁全城
Seal off the city.
把狗都牵出来 带到后面去
Get the dogs outta here now! Get them in the back!
我想他们没告诉你还有这计划吧？
I guess they didn't tell you about this part, did they?
我也不是每场会议都参加的
You think I'm at every meeting?
我在这里很安全
Look, I'm safe.
他们答应过我
They said I was safe.
上路
Let's roll!
刚才还有讯号
We had a signal earlier.
现在一点也没了
It's not working.
当你站在灾难后的遗迹前
You were standing in the wake of devastation
现在播送一条全国紧急广播
This is a national emergency broadcast.
当你等待着不可预测的变化
You were waiting on the edge of the unknown
芝加哥市已遭受猛烈攻击
Chicago has suffered a massive attack.
此时灾难即将瓢泼而至
With the cataclysm raining down
你的内心哭喊着"拯救我"
Inside's crying save me now
却无法忽视万分孤单的处境
You were there impossibly alone
离开这里！回去！
Get out of here! Go back!
一批外星人飞船包围了芝加哥
There is a ring of alien ships around Chicago.
我们的远程轰炸机刚刚被击落
Our high-range bombers were just knocked out of the sky.
他们无法突破城市上空 敌人的空中防线
They can 't get through enemy air defenses over the city.
我们的卫星也受到干扰
Our satellites have been jammed.
我们无法监控敌人的行动
We have no way to monitor the enemy's movement.
NEST的所有部队在葛瑞森空军基地待命
Our old NEST teams are on stand-down holding at Grissom Air Force Base.
距战区有10分钟路程
We're about 10 minutes from the battle zone.
特种部队正在试图进入市区
We have Special Forces trying to gain access to the city,
步兵正在外围布控
and infantry is staging at the perimeter.
等等等等 怎么搞成这样了
Excuse me, excuse me, it just doesn't make sense!
我们就看不到一点画面吗？
Can't we get any eyes in there at all?
我们的侦察机都被击落了
They keep shooting down our drones.
他们把我们变成了瞎子
They want us blind.
但我们还有微型无人侦察机 可以试试
But we do have a couple of mini-drones we're gonna try.
是谁在管无人侦察机？
Well, whoever's manning these UAV drones,
问他飞机能否改飞特朗普大厦
can we try to redirect them toward Trump Tower?
那孩子 维特维奇正在赶往芝加哥的路上
The kid, Witwickety, was on his way to Chicago.
他说霸天虎的人类间谍就在那栋大厦里！
Said some point-man human op is there for the Decepticons!
听着 如果说我知道什么 我只知道这个
Listen, if I know anything, I know this,
那小子就是外星人的跟屁虫
that kid is an alien-bad-news magnet.
我的天啊
My God.
我们要在这样的混乱之城中找到她？
We came here to find her in the middle of all that?
咱们真的要进去吗 艾普斯？
Are we really going out there, Epps?
我才不去
I'm not going in there.
没人想进去
No one's going in.
我要去
I am.
你们不去 我也要去找她
With or without you, I'll find her.
你这是在找死 山姆 你就是想这么做吗？
You're gonna get yourself killed, Sam. Is that what you want?
你就是想这么做吗？
Is that what you want?
你大老远跑来这里送死？
You came all the way out here to get yourself killed? Huh?
是吗？ 好好听我说
Listen to what I'm saying.
她是因为我才被抓来这的 你知道吗
She's here because of me. Do you understand?
听着 如果你执意要进去
Listen, if you go in this building,
即使她还活着待在里面
that's if she's even still alive,
你也没有办法能找不到她！
there's no way you're gonna be able to reach her!
那你说我该怎么办？
What do you suggest I do?
全完了
It's over.
我很抱歉这么说 但真的全完了
I'm sorry, but it's over.
不
No.
嘿 小心！
Incoming!
我们要杀他们个片甲不留
We will kill them all.
雷霆拯救队 废掉他！
Wreck ers, kill him!
这会很疼
This is going to hurt!
相当疼
A lot!
你们的领导人不明白
Your leaders will now understand.
霸天虎绝不会放过你们的星球
Decepticons will never leave your planet alone.
因此 我们需要让他们相信 我们死了
And we needed them to believe we had gone.
今日 我们以自由的名义
For today, in the name of freedom,
正式向霸天虎宣战！
we take the battle to them!
- 我看到你们的飞船爆炸！ - 飞船？
- I saw your ship blow up! - The ship?
我们根本就不在那飞船上！我们只造船不坐船 不是吗？
We were never in the ship! We designed the damn thing, didn't we?
我们都藏在第一节火箭助推器里
We were hidden in the first booster rocket to separate.
然后就按计划降落在大西洋
Splashed down back in the Atlantic, just as planned.
我们哪里也不去
We ain't going nowhere.
是的 没人能赶走我们
Yeah, no one's exiling us.
汽车人要留下来
The Autobots are staying right here.
帮你们赢得战争
We're gonna help you win this war.
他们封锁了城市 形成防御要塞
They're surrounding the city to make a fortress
所以没人能看到他们在城内的举动
so that no one can see what they're up to inside.
我们唯一的机会就是奇袭
Our only chance is the element of surprise.
我想我知道怎么能看到
I think I know where to look!
微型无人侦察机接近特朗普大厦
Mini-drone is on approach to Trump Tower.
你说山姆上那里去了？
You're telling me Sam's headed into that?
可怜的小子
Poor kid.
他可能永远到不了目的地
Probably never got close.
你会开这玩意 对吧？
So, you can fly this thing, right?
什么… 那是什么意思？马马虎虎？
What is that... What is that? What is that? So-so?
要是马马虎虎就会开 那就太悲剧了
So you so-so can fly this. That feels terrible.
我们给你殿后
We're right behind you.
好了 我们突进去
All right, we're going in!
城市已经戒严
The city is secure.
人类已经不可能阻止我们了
The humans cannot stop us.
到下午的时候
As the afternoon falls,
余下的能量柱将到达预定发射地点
the rest of the pillars will reach their launch position.
这就是多年以前我向你承诺的胜利
This is the victory I promised you so many years ago,
我们将在此携手重建塞伯坦！
where we rebuild Cybertron together!
我屈尊和你共事
I have deigned to work with you
是为了确保我们的星球能幸存下来！
that our planet may survive!
但我绝不会为你卖命！
I will never work for you!
你最好够聪明记住这种的差别
You would be wise to remember the difference.
我烦死了 我最讨厌等待
I'm so sick of this. I'm just sick of waiting.
她在哪里？
Where is she?
她在哪里？！
你挺有种的
You've got some balls.
不 山姆！
No, Sam!
不 不！
No! No, no!
卡莉！
Carly!
快跳！
Jump!
大黄蜂 开火！
Bee, fire!
大黄蜂！
Bee!
汽车人！他们还活着！
Autobots! They're alive!
霸天虎 保卫能量柱！
Decepticons, defend the pillar!
升起吊桥！找到他们！
Raise the bridges! Find them!
山姆
Sam.
你找到我了
You found me.
天涯海角我也要找到你
I'd follow you anywhere.
走吧 快走
Form a perimeter! Let's go, let's go!
你疯了吗？
Well, you're crazy.
这东西是我们的吗？
What is that? Is that us?
是军队的无人侦察机 试试看它能否运作
This thing's a military UAV. Stone, check and see if it's still working.
是的 还有动力
Yeah, it's still got power.
飞行控制中心 能接收到吗？
Flight Control, do you copy?
动一下镜头？随便做点什么呢？
Can... Can you rotate? Can you do something?
发现情况了
I think we got something.
艾普斯！是艾普斯！
Epps! We got Epps!
拜托 快启动！启动！
Come on, work! Work!
好了 把音量放大
All right, turn the volume up on that!
是他
The kid!
能把镜头转过来吗？
Can you rotate or something?
好的 好的！好了 好了 他们能看见我们
Yes, yes! Okay, okay, okay. They can see us.
芝加哥现在是中心战场 知道吗？
Chicago is ground zero, do you understand?
- 能听见吗？你明白吗？ - 维特维奇
- Can you hear us? You understand? - Witwicky.
请听好 御天敌就在这里
Please listen. Sentinel Prime is here
还有他那些太空桥的零件
and he has the pillars to his space bridge.
他们就在芝加哥河旁边的一栋大楼楼顶
They're on top of a building on Chicago River.
也就是霍奇基斯·古尔德投资大厦
It's owned by Hotchkiss Gould Investments.
那根主控柱是装置的核心 就在东南角的穹顶里
Now, the pillar that controls everything is in the southeast cupola.
你们要搞定主控柱 立刻摧毁它
You've got to destroy the pillar. You have to shoot down the pillar
不然他们就要把塞伯坦传送过来了 明白吗？
or they're going to transport Cybertron here, do you understand?
- 明白了吗？ - 什么？
- Do you understand? - What?
给我查出那栋建筑和侦察机的GPS座标！我们走！
Give me a G PS on the building and on that drone! Let's go!
正在测量 缩小范围
Mensurate those coordinates. Shorten the kill chain.
停机坪上的伙计们 给我5分钟
Guys on the tarmac, five minutes.
从这里到东南方
The southeast cupola.
好了！
All right!
得抢在被敌机发现之前采取行动
We need to move before the fighters spot us.
在这里等着 我们先去探路
Wait here until we scout a route ahead.
出发
Let's roll.
铁皮 掩护高处
Ratchet, cover high.
嘿 你觉得能用火箭弹打下主控柱吗？
Hey, think we could use that rock et to shoot down the pillar?
我们离那里有8个街区远
We're eight blocks away.
想要打中的话 得再接近点
We got to get closer to take a shot.
不用靠近 到高处去
Not closer. Higher.
得确保视野清晰
We need a clear line of sight.
那需要过河
And it's across the river.
很难悄悄潜进去
Gonna have a hell of a time trying to sneak up.
我们只有一炮的机会
We only got one shot.
一炮就足够了
One shot's all we need.
我们需要看到那幢大厦周围的情况
We got to be able to see around that building from the ground.
联络国家安全局调来该地区的监视器分布图
Get NSA to send service specs for any cameras in that area.
也许还有能用的
Maybe some are working.
交通灯 提款机 只要带摄像头的都行
Traffic lights. ATMs. Anything.
听好 想反击吗？
Listen up. You want to hit back?
那就只能穿滑翔衣飞进去
We're gonna have to wingsuit in.
这是接近那里的唯一方法
It's the only way to get close.
我不能保证每个人都能活着回来 但如果你们跟我去
I can't promise anyone a ride home, but if you're with me,
现在世界需要你们
the world needs you now.
我自己能回来 长官
I'll find my own ride home, sir.
还有谁？
Who else?
莫绍尔将军
General Morshower,
请求派兵在城南牵制敌军
requesting diversionary action to the south of the city.
我们从北面降落突入 迫使他们向东转移…
We're coming north and low. You guys drive them to the east.
汽车人必胜！ 汽车人必胜！
Autobot victory! Autobot victory!
外面的霸天虎真是太恐怖了！
That is one scary-ass Decepticon!
他们夺走了我的车厢 我需要其中的飞行装备
They got my trailer. I need that flight tech.
震荡波无法同时应付我们所有人 雷霆拯救队
Shockwave can't hunt all of us at once. Wreckers,
你们去引开他
we need a diversion.
- 我们去露一手！ - 你说得对
- Let's get some! - You got that right.
听好了 我们要设法进入那栋玻璃幕墙大楼
Listen, we're gonna circle around to that glass building.
到制高点发射火箭砲
And we'll get high enough to make the rocket shot
你们牵制他的火力
while you guys draw his fire.
- 我们走！ - 等一下！
- Let's move! - Wait a minute!
不带着我的巷战新武器我可不会放你们出去
I'm not letting you go out there without my urban combat prototypes.
- 我们得走了 Q！ - 别闹
- We got to go, Que! - Come on.
这些可是给高手用的绝妙玩意！
They're great inventions for kicking ass!
这些是什么玩意？
What are these?
那些是爆破棒 定时30秒爆炸
Those are boom-sticks. Armed in 30 seconds.
还有抓钩手套 可以爬墙
Grapple gloves, for climbing.
出去 快！行动 行动！
Go, go! Move your ass! Move, move!
行动 行动！快 快 快！
Move, move! Go, go, go!
- 移动 移动！ - 我们走！
- Move, move! - Let's go!
我们走！快点！
Let's go! Run!
- 你们上哪去？ - 不 不 不！
- Where you going? - No, no, no!
- 你们要去哪？ - 停 停 停！别走啊！
- Where you going? - Stop, stop, stop! Don't leave!
怎么能扔下弟兄呢！震荡波来了！
You never leave a 'bot behind! Shockwave's coming!
快上楼！
Go for the stairs!
艾普斯 这边走！
Epps, this way!
注意右边
Breaking right.
收到 向左
Bead. Rolling in.
又有一个来了
We got another one coming around.
从左边来了 右边也有一个
Coming around on the left side, coming around on the right side.
我们要用威利斯塔做掩护！
We're going to use Willis Tower for cover!
一旦达到高度 就往下跳！
Once we make altitude, we jump!
- 出现很多飞机！ - 碰到机头了
- A lot of airplanes out here! - Contact off the nose.
呼救！我认为他要坠毁了
Mayday! I don't think he's gonna make it.
- 求救 求救！6-1号机坠落 - 当心 当心！
- Mayday, mayday! Six-one going down. - Heads up! Heads up!
来吧 来吧 来吧
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
- 塔利在左边 - 看到他了
- Tally on the left. - Got him.
出发 出发！
Here we go! Here we go!
集中精力！
Keep it tight!
过来了
Coming around.
好了 冲 冲 冲
All right, focus, focus, focus.
塔顶有情况 六点钟方向！
Threat above tower, six o'clock!
蝗虫啊！
Locusts!
小心！注意右边！注意右边！
Look out! Breaking right! Breaking right!
- 小心 小心！ - 真要命！
- Watch out, watch out! - Holy shit!
不！ 不！ 不！
Look out, look out, look out!
让他们快跳 快跳 快跳！
Get them out, get them out, get them out!
- 所有人出去 出去！ - 跳！跳！快跳！
- Everybody out, out, out! - Jump, jump, jump!
出去！ 出去！
Get out, get out!
飞起来吧 开始行动
I'm stuck!
让他们全部离机 全部离机
Now. Get them out now! Get them out now!
救命！
Help!
注意分散 散开 散开！
Get separation. Track away, track away!
往左转 往左转！
Hard left! Hard left!
六百英尺
Six hundred feet.
六点钟方向！ 六点钟方向！
Check your six! Check your six!
他在我们后面！小心！小心！
He's on our ass! Watch out, watch out!
急转弯！
Sharp right!
大楼在正前方
Building dead ahead!
穿过缺口
Thread the needle!
开伞！ 开伞！
Pull, pull!
- 快点 我们终于到了！ - 爬到这里累死人啊！
- Come on, we're high enough! - This is a mother getting up here!
- 快把你的肥屁股挪过来！ - 来啦
- Get your fat ass over here! - I'm coming.
架上火箭炮！
Set up the rocket!
- 他们来了 - 武器配置？
- They're coming. - Weapons status?
29把机甲爆弹枪 20把D型穿刺枪
29 Bot-busters, 20 piercing D-Bot.
那里 有穹顶的大厦
There, the building with the dome.
为了牺牲的兄弟们 我们这次必须成功
For our brothers, let's make this trip worth it.
哦 天啊
Oh, God.
这栋大楼！
The building!
他们正在攻击大楼！
They're shooting at the building!
这主意可不怎么地
This is not a good idea.
- 什么？ - 待在这里不是个好主意
- What? - This is not a good idea.
- 大楼晃个不停 - 就听我说一句
- This building is unstable. - Listen, stop for a second.
我们要是不尽力一拼 那大家都得死
If we don't do what we came to do, it doesn't matter, we all die.
懂了吗？ 看你的了 加油 老兄！
Right? That's your target. Come on, man!
我才不管大楼塌不塌
I don't even care if the building collapses.
我都要吓出心脏病来了
I'm having a heart attack anyway.
大楼要倒了！
The building is going over!
- 稳住！ - 找掩体！
- Hang on! - Tak e cover!
把手举起来！
Keep your hands up!
好了！停住了！
It's okay! It stopped!
你们快看！
Guys, look!
- 来了 敌机来了！ - 大家隐蔽！
- Incoming, incoming! - Everybody hide!
别动
Don't move.
来吧
Go, go.
快跑！
Run!
火力掩护！
Cover fire!
打破玻璃！ 跳窗！
Shoot the glass! Jump out the window!
跳！
Jump!
我们要死了！
We're gonna die!
山姆 我停不下来！
Sam, I can't stop!
打碎玻璃！
Shoot the glass!
山姆！
Sam!
大家没事吧？
Is everybody okay?
你没事吧？
You okay?
那鬼东西是什么？
What the hell was that?
钻孔机器人饥渴了
Driller-bot is thirsty.
- 那个独眼恶魔正在看着我！- 什么？
- This evil thing's looking at me! - What?
他还带了个蚯蚓一样的霸天虎！
It's even got an uglier Decepticon with it!
不得不撤离！
We have to evac!
- 艾普斯中士 楼梯已经被堵住了！ - 我们被困住了！
- Sergeant Epps, the stairs are blocked! - We're trapped!
我们怎么从这里出去？嘿 快点！
Okay. How do we get out of here? Hey! Come on!
噢 主啊 只要让我活着逃出去
Oh, Lord Jesus, let me just get out of this alive.
快 得马上撤！
Move! We got to move!
霸天虎怎么老是有那么厉害的玩意？
Why do the Decepticons always get the good shit?
- 快跑！ - 我们要被吃了
- Move! - We're about to be eaten, people!
我们要死了！
We're gonna die!
- 抓紧！ - 把你的手给我！
- Hold on! - Give me your hand!
- 我来摇荡一下！ - 抓紧她！
- I'm swinging that way! - Got her!
哦 天啊！
Oh, my God!
把她丢到防火梯那里！
I'm dropping you on the fire escape!
山姆！
Sam!
离开这里！
We gotta move!
我来救你们了！
I'm coming for you!
擎天柱！
Optimus!
- 雷霆拯救队！ - 我们来了！
- Wreckers! - We're coming!
世界各地的霸天虎
Decepticons around the world,
发射能量柱
launch the pillars.
我们又迷路了！
We are so lost!
总是被遗忘
Always left out.
太棒了！
Ka-ching!
也该轮到咱们发号施令了
It's time to lay down the law.
即将搞点破坏啥的
About to bring some hurt now.
开始了！你看见了吗？
It's starting! You see it?
小心！
Look out!
山姆和卡莉哪里去了？
Where are Sam and Carly?
我们往这边跑
We'll go this way.
我就让你干护送这一件事
I give you one thing to do,
做一件事 你都能搞砸了？
one thing to do, and you drop the ball on that?
我可没答应做所有事！
I ain't signed up for all this!
外星人朝我轰炸 东奔西跑 追个不停！
Got aliens blasting at me, running around, chasing me!
我在教堂和建筑之间四处躲避并挣扎逃命！
I'm ducking through churches and buildings and all that kind of crap!
都是胡说！我可没答应这些干这个 艾普斯
This is bullshit! I ain't signed up for this, Epps.
我尽力不再吵了
I'm trying to keep it together.
- 真难得！只有你和我了！ - 卡莉！
- What a treat! You and me, alone! - Carly!
快 快！快逃！
Come on, come on! Run!
他是冲着我来的 不是你
Okay. He's after me, not you.
快跑！
Run!
你无处可藏了 小子！
You can't hide, boy!
我就喜欢看你们这些小肉虫奔逃时的狼狈样！
I just love it when your little insect feet try to run!
- 山姆！ - 跑！
- Sam!     - Run!
还以为你会为我们效命呢 小子！
I thought you were working for us, boy?
不！山姆！
No! Sam!
我的眼睛！
My eye!
目标 霸天虎！
Target the Decepticon!
山姆！
Sam!
伦诺克斯上校 你们快救救山姆！
Please, you've got to save Sam!
- 你们得救救他！ - 他在搞什么？
- You've got to save him! - What the hell is he doing?
希望这玩意管用！
This better work.
D型弹！D型弹！
D-Bots! D-Bots!
我看不见了！看不见了！
I can't see! I can't see!
山姆！
Sam!
抓住我的手！抓住刀子！用刀割！
It's on my hand! Grab the knife! Knife!
- 我在试！ - 刀 刀 刀！
- I'm trying! - Knife, knife, knife, knife, knife!
炸弹要爆炸！炸弹要…
The bomb's gonna blow! The bomb's gonna...
你们这些人渣！
You human scum!
- 只有二十秒炸弹要爆炸了！ - 什么炸弹？
- We got 20 seconds on that bomb! - What bomb?
看见那炸弹没？
You see that bomb?
- 快割 快割 快割！ - 知道了！
- Cut it, cut it, cut it! - I got it!
还有多少时间？
How long do we have?
我要宰了你们！
I'm gonna kick you!
割 割 割！
Cut, cut, cut!
我要杀…
I'm gonna kill...
他死掉了
Well, he's dead.
嘿 现在大黄蜂要去跟其他汽车人汇合
Hey, Bee's going to run with the rest of the Autobots
- 到河边去与我们会合 - 好的
- and meet us at the edge of the river. - All right.
它把我们吸进来了！我也不想这样！
It sucked me in! There was nothing I could do!
这下麻烦大了…
This is a total cluster...
我们必须过河
We got to get across the river.
你看见那个了吗？卡莉说太空桥控制柱
You see that? She said the control pillar
- 就在第一个穹顶里 - 好的
- was in that first cupola. - All right.
快跑！行动！前进！
Let's go! Move! Let's move!
战斧导弹已经发射
Tomahawks are inbound.
预计20分钟后到达
ETA, twenty minutes.
我进入路况监视系统了
I'm in the traffic cameras.
有4名汽车人被俘
Four Autobots are captured.
噢 天哪 我们孤立无援了
Oh, my God. We're helpless.
不管什么情况 讯号闪得越来越快
Whatever's set to happen, with those pulses getting faster,
肯定要出事了
it's gonna happen soon.
没有看到擎天柱
No sign of Optimus.
我们怎么才能把这些桥降下来？
How do we get these bridges down?
全体散开 查看情况
Spread out. Check in there.
艾普斯！
Epps!
艾普斯 我找你半天了 你干什么呢？
Epps, I've been looking for your ass. How you doing?
撤退没有用 更糟的是
Retirement is wack. Even worse,
我们无法渡河到达那栋大楼
we can't get across the river to that building,
而对岸的汽车人全被霸天虎包围了
and the Autobots are upstairs, surrounded.
把镜头转过来一点
Just pan the camera around, all right?
好的 转过来 你来做
All right. Pan... Pan right. That's you.
试着进入大桥主控室
Try getting into the bridge control room.
他们在那里干嘛？ 光站着不动？
What are they doing? They're just standing there.
加油 达奇 想办法黑进大桥主控电脑
Hang on. Dutch, see if you can hack into the bridge.
长官 海豹特种部队报到
Sir, SEALs are here.
干得好 小伙子们！你们来了几个人？
It's a good day, boys! What do you got?
10人特种小组 长官 任务是引导战斧导弹
Got a 10-man SEAL unit, sir, tasked with vectoring Tomahawks.
- 还有多久？ - 15分钟
- How long?   - Fifteen.
- 你们都是我的俘虏！ - 放松点 我们投降了
- You're my prisoners! - Take it easy. We surrender.
别碰我
Get off me.
别碰我！
Get off me!
好了 装填口径40毫米的碎片弹 切换到自动射击模式
All right, you're gonna need your 40 Mike-Mikes and frags. Go full auto.
爆炸的震荡波能让它们短路
The vibrations jack up their circuits.
狙击手 射瞎他们的眼睛
Snipers, shoot for the eyes.
目标就在那栋建筑的顶部 现在出击
All right, your target is up on top of that building, that cupola.
你们太愚蠢了 汽车人
How doomed you are, Autobots.
连这么简单的道理都不懂
You simply fail to understand
少数人的利益必须服从大众的需求
that the needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few.
启动太空桥
Activating the bridge.
他们好像在守卫什么东西
They happy about something.
我们已经到了他们母舰的中心
We're in the heart of their ship.
让咱们帮他们开一会儿
Let's give 'em a little ride.
让我们来把这船掀个底朝天
We gonna screw this ship up.
这是128位的二进制密码
It's a 128K binary encryption code.
很难破解
It's difficult.
但不适用于我 我进去了 放下吊桥
But not for me. I'm in. Bridge down.
桥面被放下来了！有人在暗中帮助我们！
The bridge is coming down! Someone's watching over us!
快点！出发！
Come on! Let's go!
“很荣幸能跟你合作 西摩”
"Pleasure working with you, Seymour."
我相信你会这么说的
I believe you're supposed to say.
做得好 达奇
Good job, Dutch.
（非常感谢（荷兰语））
放开我！
Get off me!
快点！他们正在启动能量柱！
Hurry! They're triggering the pillars!
战俘？ 你们还收战俘？
Prisoners? You're keeping prisoners?
是的
Yes.
你得教他们学乖点
You need to teach them about respect.
以前是公事公办 现在是私人恩怨 你懂我的意思吗？
This was all business, but now it's personal, do you understand me?
我懂 没有战俘 只有战利品
I understand. No prisoners, only trophies.
大黄蜂 我觉得他们想要杀了我们…
Bee, I think they're going to kill us.
- 你 你的死期到了 - 等等 等等！
- You, your time is up. - Wait, wait, wait!
我们投降了！我们是战俘
We surrendered! We're your prisoners.
- 快走！ - 我们就不能谈谈吗？
- Move it! - Can't we talk this out?
我们全都是好小子！我是说…
We're all a bunch of good chaps! I mean you no...
为什么…
Why did you...
再见了 我的老朋友
Good-bye, my old friend.
现在 你是我的了！
You're mine now.
别碰我！
Get off me!
- 我得去救他 - 什么？
- I got to help him. - What?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
- 我要去救他 - 山姆 你救不了的
- I got to help him. - Sam, you can't help him.
转过身去
Turn around.
我们… 我们曾有过很多的回忆
We... We gave 'em a hell of a run.
成功了 聪明鬼！我们成功了！
We did it, Brains! We did it!
把飞船拆成废铁吧！
Rip this ship apart!
- 我们干得真棒 聪明鬼 你和我 - 是啊
- We had a nice run, Brains, you and me. - Yeah,
不过我们死定了
we gonna die.
哇 哇 哇！好了宝贝！跟我们一起来吧！
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Okay, baby! You all come with us!
我们走！你们跟紧地面部队！走！
Go! You guys, follow that ground team! Go!
快 快 快走！
Move, move, move!
艾普斯 你们上3楼！我们要上45楼！
Epps, third floor! We're going to 45!
你们两个狙击手留在这里！
All right. Two snipers, right here!
报告位置！
All right, dock up!
3分钟后就跳伞！
We jump in three minutes!
安置火力点 这边
Set up shop right here.
各就各位
Set up.
在楼下
I'm downstairs.
有5个目标 还有震荡波 就在我们脚下
We got five targets and Shockwave right below us.
准备跳伞！
Stand by to jump!
好了 我们走！准备 准备
All right, let's go! Get ready, get ready.
出发！
Go!
狙击手 敲了他们的眼睛
Snipers, take out their eyes.
好了 爆破组 安装炸弹
All right, demo team, let's crank steel.
即时引爆！
Turning steel!
没我命令不准开火！
Don't fire till I tell you!
快！
Go!
干得不错！
Good job, kid!
开火！
Fire!
- 我们打到他了！ - 是啊！
- We got him!     - Yeah!
他在逃跑！
He's on the run!
汽车人 攻击！
Autobots, attack!
火力集中到桥上！
Mortar that bridge!
现在这是我们的世界了！
It's our world now!
开始传送！
Commence transport!
哦 天啊 天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
擎天柱！
Optimus!
去死吧！
You die!
不！
No!
给我下来 御天敌！
Get down here, Sentinel!
擎天柱
Optimus,
你忘了你的立场！
you forget your place!
我给你带来了塞伯坦 你的故乡
I bring you Cybertron, your home,
你依然要站在人类那边吗？
and still you choose humanity.
是你教会我自由权利归众生
You were the one who taught me freedom is everyone's right.
我会重启能量柱！
I will retrigger that pillar!
那你得先过我这关！
Then you'll have to go through me!
听着 我得去帮忙
Okay, I've got to try and help.
- 我自己去 你留在这里 - 你别去 别去
- I have to. You stay here. - Don't you go. Don't go.
你会没事的好吗？我保证 我得到主控能量柱那去
You'll be fine, okay? I promise. I got to get to that pillar.
拿下能量柱！
Charge the pillar!
汽车人来了！
We got Autobots!
我需要支援！
Reinforcements!
霸天虎飞船 向擎天柱开火！
Decepticon ships, fire at Optimus!
发射！我现在就需要那些战斧导弹！
We're taking fire! I need those Tomahawks now!
第一波导弹即将到达
First wave inbound.
我们必须掩护擎天柱！
We've got to cover for Optimus!
霸天虎！ 夺回能量柱！
Decepticons, trigger the pillar!
重启能量柱！
Restart that pillar!
启动那根能量柱
Trigger the pillars.
我挡不住了！我需要躲避一下！
I can't hold them! The ships have us pinned!
不！
No!
导弹到达 还有10秒！危险接近！
Inbound, 10 seconds! Danger close!
解码M-L-E-F 14250！
Mark-Lima-Echo-Echo, 14250!
确信表面接触
Positive surface contact.
- 请给座标 - 已获取目标
- Target I.D. - Target acquired.
- 迪伦！等等！ - 不！
- Dylan! Wait! - No!
迪伦！
Dylan!
住手！住手！
Stop! Stop!
不！
No!
你不能这样做 好吗？
You can't do this, okay?
对我来说只有一个未来
There's only one future for me.
塞伯坦
Cybertron,
你终于得救了
you are saved,
在最后时刻
at last.
你是来向我投降的吗？
Have you come to surrender?
- 这一切都值得吗？ - 当然了
- Was it all worth it? - Obviously.
你费尽心机救回了御天敌
All your work to bring Sentinel back
而现在他却夺走了你所有的权力
and now clearly he has all the power.
我都有点替你感到难过了
It's actually almost tragic.
你胆敢教训我 奴隶？
You dare lecture me, slave?
就算你的霸天虎最终征服这个星球
Your Decepticons finally conquering this planet,
他们的领袖也不会是你
and yet, their leader won't be you!
一定是我！ 永远是我！
It will be me! It will always be me.
再过个几分钟
In any minute now,
除了当御天敌的婊子你什么都不是
you'll be nothing but Sentinel's bitch.
小心
Rock et!
去死！
Die!
你在选阵营时
You chose sides?
选错了
You chose wrong.
你一直是我们中最勇敢的战士
Always the bravest of us!
但你总是无法做出艰难抉择
But you could never make the hard decisions!
我们的星球会生存下去
Our planet will survive!
不！
No!
我们曾经是神 我们全都是
We were gods once. All of us.
- 但在这里… - 求你住手！
- But here...     - Please!
神只能有一个！
...there will only be one!
这是我的星球！
This is my planet!
我刚刚拯救了另一个世界！
I just saved a whole other world.
你以为你是英雄？你以为你是个英雄吗？
You think you're a hero, huh? You think you're a hero?
不 我只不过是个送信的
No. I'm just a messenger.
太空桥仍然连接着！
The pillar's still connected!
小心点！
Bring it up!
- 大黄蜂！开始干吧！ - 来吧 来吧！动手 动手！
- Bee! Let's do this! - Let's go, let's go! Move, move!
它仍在运作！
Pillar's still connected!
摧毁那根能量柱！
Rip that pillar down!
现在 我们应该停战
Now, we need a truce.
我只不过想重掌领导权
All I want is to be back in charge.
此外…
Besides,
没有我你能做什么 擎天柱？
who would you be without me, Prime?
咱们走着瞧
Time to find out.
擎天柱 我所想要的
Optimus, all I ever wanted
不过是我们种族的延续
was the survival of our race.
你必须明白 我不得不背叛你的原因
You must see why I had to betray you.
你并没有背叛我
You didn't betray me.
你背叛了你自己
You betrayed yourself.
不 擎天柱！
No, Optimus!
山姆
Sam.
我爱你
I love you.
在这世上我只需要你
You're the only thing I need in this world,
我会为你做任何事 我保证
and I'll do anything to make it up to you, I promise.
你可要信守承诺
I'm going to hold you to that.
不要再放我走了
Just never let me go.
我保证
I promise.
戒指？
Rings.
我爱这辆车！
I love this car.
大黄蜂 你得悠着点
Bee, you've got to slow it down.
悠着点来 好吗？
You got to slow way down, okay?
我只想帮个忙 老兄
I'm just trying to help out.
战争之中
In any war
总会有暴风雨之间的平静
there are calms between storms.
你小子很勇敢
You fought bravely.
有时候我们会失去信念
There will be days when we lose faith.
有时候我们的盟友会背叛我们
Days when our allies turn against us.
但是我们绝对不会放弃地球
But the day will never come that we forsake this planet
和地球上的人类
and its people.
是否你感到冰冷无助？
Do you feel cold and lost in desperation
你满怀希望但最终充满绝望
You build up hope but failure's all you've known
让这些不快逝去
And let it go
我的美好未来就从这一刻开始
That's what I call the start of a beautiful future.
逮捕他
Arrest him.
我够本了！
It was worth it!
- 把他带走！ - 我愿意为爱坐牢！我不在乎！
- Get him out of here! - I'd go to jail for love! I don't care!
开始吧 送我进去！我想坐牢！我想进去
Go ahead, take me in! I want to go in! Let's go in.
快点 夏洛特 快把我抓起来！
Come on, Charlotte, take me in right now!
执 行 制 片 史蒂芬·斯皮尔伯格 迈克尔·贝
是否你感到冰冷无助？
Do you feel cold and lost in desperation
执 行 制 片 布莱恩·戈德诺 马克·瓦拉迪恩
摄影指导 阿米尔·莫克利
艺术指导 奈杰尔·菲尔普斯
你满怀希望但最终充满绝望
You build up hope but failure's all you've known
剪辑 罗杰·巴顿 威廉·戈登堡 美国剪辑师工会 乔尔·内古龙
服 装 设 计 黛博拉 L·斯科特
音乐 斯蒂夫·贾布隆斯基
记住这所有的悲哀和沮丧
Remember all the sadness and frustration
视 觉 特 效 斯科特·法拉 美国电影摄影师协会
希亚·拉博夫
乔什·杜哈明
让这些不快逝去
And let it go
泰瑞斯·吉布森
罗茜·汉丁顿-惠特莉
帕特里克·德姆西
凯文·杜恩
然后让时光冲刷掉这些不快
Let it go Let it go
朱丽叶·怀特
肯·郑
艾伦·图代克 格伦·莫肖尔 莱斯特·斯贝特
约翰·马尔科维奇
弗兰西斯·麦克多蒙德
选 角 导 演 丹尼斯·查米安 美国演员协会
联合制片 肯·贝茨 阿莱格拉·克莱格
然后让时光冲刷掉这些不快
Let it go Let it go
唐·墨菲/汤姆·德桑托 摄制
迪·博纳文图拉制片公司 摄制
伊恩·布莱斯 摄制
迈克尔·贝 作品
♪ 你曾是我的良心
♪ You were my conscience,
♪ 坚毅如磐石的你现在像流水一般孱弱
♪ So solid, now you're like water
♪ 我们开始被覆没
♪ And we started drowning,
♪ 比我们想要的更深
♪ Not like we'd sink any farther
♪ 但是我让我的心离去
♪ But I let my heart go,
♪ 它的某些地方陷入了无尽的深渊
♪ it's somewhere down the bottom.
♪ 但是我会找寻一个新的
♪ But I'll get a new one,
♪ 希望来代替你偷走的那一个
♪ Come back for the hope that you've stolen.
♪ 我会去阻止世界
♪ I'll stop the whole world,
♪ I'll stop the whole world
♪ 变成一个怪物活生生的吞噬我们
♪ From turning into a monster and eating us alive
♪ 难道你没有考虑过我们怎样才能幸存下来
♪ Don't you ever wonder how we survive?
♪ 好吧，现在你走了 这个世界是我们的了
♪ Well now that you're gone, the world is ours
♪ 啊…
♪ Ahh ah ah ahh ah ah
♪ 我只是普通人
♪ I'm only human,
♪ 我已经得到了我的精神支柱
♪ I've got a skeleton in me
♪ 不过我不是那个
♪ but I'm not the villain,
♪ 尽管你一直鼓吹的小人
♪ despite what you're always preaching.
♪ 一个背信弃义的人
♪ Call me a traitor,
♪ 我只是正在收集你的受害者
♪ I'm just collecting your victims
♪ 他们浴火重生
♪ And they're getting stronger
♪ 我听到他们的呼唤
♪ And I hear them calling (calling, Calling)
♪ 我会去阻止世界
♪ I'll stop the whole world,
♪ I'll stop the whole world
♪ 变成一个怪物活生生的吞噬我们
♪ From turning into a monster and eating us alive
♪ 难道你没有考虑过我们怎样才能幸存下来
♪ Don't you ever wonder how we survive?
♪ 好吧，现在你走了，这世界…
♪ Well now that you're gone, the world...
♪ 我会去阻止世界
♪ I'll stop the whole world,
♪ I'll stop the whole world
♪ 变成一个怪物活生生的吞噬我们
♪ From turning into a monster eating us alive
♪ 难道你没有考虑过我们怎样才能幸存下来
♪ Don't you ever wonder how we survive?
♪ 好吧，现在你走了，这世界是我们的了
♪ Now that you're gone, the world is ours